<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agasthyamala on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/tags/agasthyamala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agasthyamala on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2008-2025 Sadique Ali.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 03:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sadique.io/tags/agasthyamala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The trek to Agasthyamala - 3</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2008/05/24/the-trek-to-agasthyamala-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 03:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2008/05/24/the-trek-to-agasthyamala-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the forest guards were convinced we didn&amp;rsquo;t carry anything illegal and we were introduced to our guide, we set out on to the trail. I was already at the front of the pack and soon my friend Manu joined me. Ans so, we began to set the pace for the group. Most of the pictures were taken by my friends in the group, and they were very slow to say they least, because they were shooting pictures on every corner of the trail. And luckily for me, the guide chose to stick with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The trek to Agasthyamala - 2</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2008/05/02/the-trek-to-agasthyamala-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2008 17:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2008/05/02/the-trek-to-agasthyamala-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the breakfast, it was time to start the real journey. We collected our bags and set out for the Forest Departments check post. The scenery of the Estate was so breath taking. Although it is a Tea estate, it has been almost a decade since any tea-making really took place here. It was shut down because of constant struggle between Tata Tea and the Trade Unions. Most of the employees made makeshift homes and settled down in the estate. The situation is really illustrated by the state of the tea-processing factory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The trek to Agasthyamala - 1</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2008/04/26/the-trek-to-agasthyamala-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 05:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2008/04/26/the-trek-to-agasthyamala-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was early March, the college was going forward with its usual disregard for people who were not much interested in what went on in there. My friend group decided to go for a trek, up Agasthymala, which is the second tallest peak in Kerala.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The trip involved taking an early morning bus to the Bonaccord Tea Estate in Vidhura, a village on the slopes of the Western Ghats. From there we would go to a base station about 15 kilometers, in to the deep forest and then we would climb the peak.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
