<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redis on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/tags/redis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Redis on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2008-2025 Sadique Ali.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:10:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sadique.io/tags/redis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Handling Deserialization errors in Spring Redis Sessions</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2016/11/02/handling-deserialization-errors-in-spring-redis-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2016/11/02/handling-deserialization-errors-in-spring-redis-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges of using storing spring sessions in Redis is that the objects that gets stored as part of a session often undergoes changes as the application evolves and these changes cause de-serialization exceptions to be thrown after a deployment when a session created before the deployment is presented to the application. This blog post discusses a method to work around this issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Redis auto-configuration for Spring Boot Session</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2016/07/16/controlling-redis-auto-configuration-for-spring-boot-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 22:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2016/07/16/controlling-redis-auto-configuration-for-spring-boot-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been using Spring Boot, chances are that you are using the Spring Session library to handle sessions. Spring Session has the ability to persist the sessions to various data stores, including Redis. The default behaviors of Spring Boot when combined with Spring Session is to start using Redis as the session store the moment &lt;code&gt;spring-session-data-redis&lt;/code&gt; is detected in the class path, thereby making it hard to conditionally turn Redis support ON and OFF. This blog post explores why this is the default behavior and presents a solution to control this behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Rate Limiting in Rails - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/10/13/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/10/13/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first part of this series can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://sadique.io/blog/2013/10/12/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails-part-1/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first part of this series looked at how to implement basic rate limiting in a Rails application. However, as pointed out in the improvements section, the implementation was not complete - it did not provide clients enough information about the rate limiting that is in place and how long they should wait before making further requests once they hit the limit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Rate Limiting in Rails - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/10/12/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/10/12/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The second part of this series can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://sadique.io/blog/2013/10/13/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails-part-2/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rate limiting or throttling is the practice of limiting how frequently legitimate users of a web service can access the service. Rate limiting is often put in place to prevent the hogging of resources by a sub set of the users of the system. Rate limiting works by responding with error messages when a client exceeds their allocated share of requests within a predefined time window. In addition to the error message, the response should also include information as to when rate limit will be reset so that the client can continue accessing the system after the reset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
