<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talk on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/tags/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in talk on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sadique.io/tags/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>D3.js Workshop</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/01/d3.js-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/01/d3.js-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did a &lt;a href=&#34;http://d3js.org&#34;&gt;d3.js&lt;/a&gt; workshop at ThoughtWorks Bangalore yesterday (31st
July, 2012). I split the workshop in to two parts. The first was a basic
introduction to d3.js - SVG, Scaling, Axes etc. The second part
was an exercise to hack together a Scatterplot with some Cricket
dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 30 people attended the workshop. I spent too much time on the first part and hence we did not have enough
time to complete the second part. This was the first ever workshop I have done
and my time plan was way off. I should fix it the next time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XConf 6 - Data, My Heart!</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/16/xconf-6-data-my-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/16/xconf-6-data-my-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday,  Srijayanth Sridhar (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/craftybones&#34;&gt;@craftybones&lt;/a&gt;) and I gave a talk at XConf, ThoughtWorks India&amp;rsquo;s internal conference series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked about visualising data, and the various visualisations that one could use to answer questions about the dataset you have. We looked at two particular datasets -  one showing the consumption of juice at the fresh juice counter in office and one about Indian and Pakistani players. We looked at various visualizations like Area charts, Box Plots, Chord Diagrams, Line Charts, Pie Charts, Donut Charts, Small Multiples, Spark Lines, Stack Charts and Treemaps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VodQA NCR: Maintaining Large Test Suites</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/06/24/vodqa-ncr-maintaining-large-test-suites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/06/24/vodqa-ncr-maintaining-large-test-suites/</guid>
      <description>Srijayanth Sridhar and I did a talk yesterday at vodQA NCR.
The talk was about what makes maintenance of large test suites a pain and the things that have worked for us and we have seen work for other teams.
It went well and we got a lot of good feedback from the crowd. The prezi for the talk is below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banyan Tree: Football and Politics</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2011/12/05/banyan-tree-football-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2011/12/05/banyan-tree-football-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>I recently did a talk on football and the politics behind it, as part of the Banyan Tree talk series at ThoughtWorks. The slides from the talk can be found hereon Speakerdeck.It was great fun for me. I thought I did well.
It is a topic I know my way around. The history behind the El Clasico - the Spanish civil war, Franco, the trade unions and Di Stefano was discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>