<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>D3.js on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/tags/d3.js/</link>
    <description>Recent content in D3.js on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2008-2025 Sadique Ali.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sadique.io/tags/d3.js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curse of the Community Shield?</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/15/curse-of-the-community-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/15/curse-of-the-community-shield/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Click on the image to see the visualisation:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sadique.io/visualizations/community_shield/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sadique.io/images/community_shield.png&#34; alt=&#34;Community Shield visualisation&#34; title=&#34;Community Shield Visualisation&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The football season in Europe began this weekend with countries hosting&#xA;their equivalents of the &lt;em&gt;Super Cup&lt;/em&gt;. For those confused as to what a&#xA;super cup, the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Super_cup&#34;&gt;Wikipedia entry&lt;/a&gt; is a good&#xA;starting point. Super cups, at least in European national&#xA;leagues are curtain-raisers for the season.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FA &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FA_Community_Shield&#34;&gt;Community Shield&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;is England&amp;rsquo;s Super Cup and it pits the winners of the FA Cup against the&#xA;winners of the Premier League from the previous season. This year&amp;rsquo;s game saw Manchester City&#xA;beat Chelsea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Winning the Community Shield at the beginning of the&#xA;season is considered a bad omen by a lot of football fans - an indicator that the team who win it&#xA;would not win the subsequent league season. This supposed curse is&#xA;widely discussed in&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redcafe.net/f6/curse-community-shield-165424/&#34;&gt;fan forums&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;and&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2005/jan/26/theknowledge.sport&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt;. And&#xA;what would be complete on the Internet without a &lt;a href=&#34;http://9gag.com/gag/5030472&#34;&gt;dinosaur thinking&#xA;aloud&lt;/a&gt; about it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D3.js Workshop</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/01/d3.js-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/01/d3.js-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did a &lt;a href=&#34;http://d3js.org&#34;&gt;d3.js&lt;/a&gt; workshop at ThoughtWorks Bangalore yesterday (31st&#xA;July, 2012). I split the workshop in to two parts. The first was a basic&#xA;introduction to d3.js - SVG, Scaling, Axes etc. The second part&#xA;was an exercise to hack together a Scatterplot with some Cricket&#xA;dataset.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 30 people attended the workshop. I spent too much time on the first part and hence we did not have enough&#xA;time to complete the second part. This was the first ever workshop I have done&#xA;and my time plan was way off. I should fix it the next time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualisation - How European clubs dominate their leagues</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/21/visualisation-how-european-clubs-dominate-their-leagues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/21/visualisation-how-european-clubs-dominate-their-leagues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://sadique.io/visualizations/league_champions/index.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see the visualisation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a visualization showing how various European football clubs have&#xA;dominated their respective national leagues over various time&#xA;periods. The visualization shows data for England, France, Germany,&#xA;Italy, Netherlands and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The visualization is self-explanatory. You can choose a league to view&#xA;from the dropdown and then choose the sliders to select an era for which you want to look&#xA;at the data. For fine adjustment, after clicking on either slider, you&#xA;can use your keyboard to select a time period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XConf 6 - Data, My Heart!</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/16/xconf-6-data-my-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/16/xconf-6-data-my-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday,  Srijayanth Sridhar (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/craftybones&#34;&gt;@craftybones&lt;/a&gt;) and I gave a talk at XConf, ThoughtWorks India&amp;rsquo;s internal conference series.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We talked about visualising data, and the various visualisations that one could use to answer questions about the dataset you have. We looked at two particular datasets -  one showing the consumption of juice at the fresh juice counter in office and one about Indian and Pakistani players. We looked at various visualizations like Area charts, Box Plots, Chord Diagrams, Line Charts, Pie Charts, Donut Charts, Small Multiples, Spark Lines, Stack Charts and Treemaps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian and Pakistani cricketers - who make better debuts?</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/05/11/indian-and-pakistani-cricketers-who-make-better-debuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/05/11/indian-and-pakistani-cricketers-who-make-better-debuts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently a friend and I had an argument about who makes better debuts among Indian and Pakistani cricket players. Now, I am not into cricket. But I do watch the odd matches here and there and am generally aware of what is going on in the game. My stand was that Pakistani players make better debuts compared to Indian players, while my friend was adamant that Indian players make better debuts. My friend is more of a cricket guy than I ever was and he asked me what is the basis of my stand. It was just a gut feel for me and I had to leave it as there was no way for me to prove that my gut feel was correct. But I did want to try, though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to see if I could prove my theory. Luckily, Cricinfo has all this data, although they dont make it easy for you to get it. I wrote some scripts to pull this data and decided to visualise this using the awesome d3 library. In the end, this became more about figuring out d3 than winning the argument, but doing this was fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
