<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Football on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/categories/football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Football on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2008-2025 Sadique Ali.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 21:08:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sadique.io/categories/football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Inverness</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2016/06/05/on-inverness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 21:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2016/06/05/on-inverness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, I was in the Scottish Highlands - soaking in the beauty of the city of Inverness, hiking through the South Loch Ness trail and traveling across the Black Isle. It was a wonderful trip - one that I wish was longer. This was a trip that invoked so many memories in me - among other things, of a man whose voice was part of growing up. A voice that traveled from the BBC Studios in the United Kingdom halfway across the globe and into a radio set in South Malabar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving up the Samba for the Tiki-taka</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/21/giving-up-the-samba-for-the-tiki-taka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/21/giving-up-the-samba-for-the-tiki-taka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A shot flew over the bar. The goal keeper showed great urgency in&#xA;collecting the ball from behind the goal. Instead of kicking it forward, he pushed the ball&#xA;gently out to the centre back. As the opposition forward streamed&#xA;forward to close him down, the defender moved the ball swiftly and pushed it to&#xA;the right back who was level with the penalty box. Another push and the&#xA;central mid fielder was brought in to the play. A through ball to the&#xA;left found the player on the left wing and as the opposing&#xA;right back zoomed in to focus, he played it back to his left back. As&#xA;the left back controlled the ball, his&#xA;team repositioned themselves to start from scratch all over again. To build&#xA;from the back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have watched football in the recent past, you would recognise a&#xA;pattern here. You would see the unmistakable Barcelona blueprint. Except&#xA;that I am not describing Barcelona. Not even Spain. In fact when the&#xA;initial shot flew over the bar, there was no collective sigh of relief&#xA;from a crowd &lt;a href=&#34;%22http://mkbarcelona.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/200311-005.jpg%22&#34;&gt;packed till the heavens&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;there was no eager ball boy to throw the ball back at the keeper and&#xA;there was no one in the dug out shouting instructions at the&#xA;players. Hell, there was not even a dug out near the touch line. The&#xA;keeper ran to the construction site where the ball had found it&amp;rsquo;s way&#xA;through and ran back all the way to get the play restarted. As he was&#xA;still was running back, the left back of my opponents walked back to his&#xA;position, his face embellished with a smile bore out of his pride&#xA;of having bent his shot around the cashew tree inside the&#xA;ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curse of the Community Shield?</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/15/curse-of-the-community-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/15/curse-of-the-community-shield/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Click on the image to see the visualisation:&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sadique.io/visualizations/community_shield/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sadique.io/images/community_shield.png&#34; alt=&#34;Community Shield visualisation&#34; title=&#34;Community Shield Visualisation&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The football season in Europe began this weekend with countries hosting&#xA;their equivalents of the &lt;em&gt;Super Cup&lt;/em&gt;. For those confused as to what a&#xA;super cup, the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Super_cup&#34;&gt;Wikipedia entry&lt;/a&gt; is a good&#xA;starting point. Super cups, at least in European national&#xA;leagues are curtain-raisers for the season.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FA &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FA_Community_Shield&#34;&gt;Community Shield&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;is England&amp;rsquo;s Super Cup and it pits the winners of the FA Cup against the&#xA;winners of the Premier League from the previous season. This year&amp;rsquo;s game saw Manchester City&#xA;beat Chelsea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Winning the Community Shield at the beginning of the&#xA;season is considered a bad omen by a lot of football fans - an indicator that the team who win it&#xA;would not win the subsequent league season. This supposed curse is&#xA;widely discussed in&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redcafe.net/f6/curse-community-shield-165424/&#34;&gt;fan forums&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;and&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2005/jan/26/theknowledge.sport&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt;. And&#xA;what would be complete on the Internet without a &lt;a href=&#34;http://9gag.com/gag/5030472&#34;&gt;dinosaur thinking&#xA;aloud&lt;/a&gt; about it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualisation - How European clubs dominate their leagues</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/21/visualisation-how-european-clubs-dominate-their-leagues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/21/visualisation-how-european-clubs-dominate-their-leagues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://sadique.io/visualizations/league_champions/index.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see the visualisation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a visualization showing how various European football clubs have&#xA;dominated their respective national leagues over various time&#xA;periods. The visualization shows data for England, France, Germany,&#xA;Italy, Netherlands and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The visualization is self-explanatory. You can choose a league to view&#xA;from the dropdown and then choose the sliders to select an era for which you want to look&#xA;at the data. For fine adjustment, after clicking on either slider, you&#xA;can use your keyboard to select a time period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banyan Tree: Football and Politics</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2011/12/05/banyan-tree-football-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2011/12/05/banyan-tree-football-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently did a talk on football and the politics behind it, as part of the Banyan Tree talk series at ThoughtWorks. The slides from the talk can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://speakerdeck.com/u/sdqali/p/football-as-a-lense&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on Speakerdeck.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;It was great fun for me. I thought I did well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a topic I know my way around. The history behind the El Clasico - the Spanish civil war, Franco, the trade unions and Di Stefano was discussed. We also looked at The Old Firm. I also talked about Athletic Bilbao&amp;rsquo;s use of football as a form of cultural resistance. The last parts of the talk were about multiculturalism, united Europe and football as a globalized game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Athletic - The European campaign and a Basque special</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2010/02/06/athletic-the-european-campaign-and-a-basque-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2010/02/06/athletic-the-european-campaign-and-a-basque-special/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last time I wrote about Athletic, they were relinquishing at the bottom of the La Liga table, their record as one among the only three clubs in La Liga to have never got relegated in threat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than a year later, things are really looking up at The Catedral. They managed to finish at seventh in the La Liga last season, qualifying for the Europa Liga. They are flying in Europa Liga this season, they are almost on the verge of breaking into the European qualifying positions again, they have one of La Liga&amp;rsquo;s most promising youngsters in Iker Muniain, and in typical Basque tradition, they are going to play in the knockout matches in Europe with &amp;lsquo;Euskadi&amp;rsquo; proudly written in front of their shirts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missing the game</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2010/02/05/missing-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2010/02/05/missing-the-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have continued to watch and follow the beautiful game, save for my first few months in Bangalore. This is supposed to be a metro. Well, apparently a metro where people don&amp;rsquo;t give a damn about football. After taking a cable connection, I soon realized that I will have to beg with the cable guy to put on ESPNStar so that I could watch EPL. Pretty soon, Hathway had some issues with ESPNStar, which meant there was no way I could watch ESPNStar. On the weekends, I tried to pursue the cable operator to put on NEO Sports, at least I could watch Bundes Liga and Serie A. He would not budge, and I had to endure the interesting argument that &amp;ldquo;NEO Cricket and NEO Sports are the same&amp;rdquo;. It was tough to accept - in the small village of Vadakkethala, where I hail from, I could watch as much football as I wanted. In Malappuram, if you are a cable TV operator and don&amp;rsquo;t put on channels with football on, God save you. So Bangalore&amp;rsquo;s apparent indifference to football was frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yet another week in Bangalore</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2009/08/16/yet-another-week-in-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2009/08/16/yet-another-week-in-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yet another week of my Bangalore life has unfolded. It was tougher, and better than the first two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I learned lots of new stuff, stuff that would greatly help me in my profession. I made friends with new people. But most important of all, I got some feedback on some of the things I do in life. It was kind of very scary, to be honest. But then I realized that the feedback will let me improve. I am trying hard to use the feedback in the most positive way possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Journal</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2009/08/08/bangalore-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2009/08/08/bangalore-journal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my 13th day in Bangalore. And the first week of my training at ToughtWorks has gone by. I learned lots of stuff, talked to some great people and made friends with some of them. I still have not overcome the difficulties of adapting to life in the City. May be I will soon, or I never will.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had planned to post everyday about my experiences in TWU. But I did not have much time. The sessions last till 5:00 pm, and then I will be very tired to do much. I am really missing football. I had hoped to play with my friend Aneesh on last Sunday, but we were not allowed to play as one old guy who turned up decided that only regulars could play there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When I used to love Cricket</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2009/02/26/when-i-used-to-love-cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2009/02/26/when-i-used-to-love-cricket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking a tour through the orkut albums of some of my friends from my school, I happened to see a photo of us in the playground, shot after a game of cricket. And there I was - thin, short and most surprisingly for me, with a cricket bat in my hand. True, I have seen the photo a number of times, I had even commented on it, but today, the bat in my hand reminding me solidly that I once used to play cricket and love it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Athletic Bilbao - Warriors in a world of Mercenaries</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2008/11/08/athletic-bilbao-warriors-in-a-world-of-mercenaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2008/11/08/athletic-bilbao-warriors-in-a-world-of-mercenaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modern day football has become a professional game of the highest order, where money speaks loudest, player loyalty is as rare as silverware for ManCity, and big clubs poach youngsters from clubs with smaller financial muscle, with trick or crook.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amidst all these there still stand a club, who recruit players from their locality, born to their tribe and is even ready to forsake their top-flight status, in order to stick to their principles. Athletic Bilbao, the Spanish club, is a Basque institution that adheres to their &amp;rsquo;la cantera&amp;rsquo; policy so passionately that, no non-Basque player has played for them since 1912.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
