<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/categories/internet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2008-2025 Sadique Ali.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sadique.io/categories/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The fear of being wrong on the Internet</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/10/15/the-fear-of-being-wrong-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/10/15/the-fear-of-being-wrong-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All of us have opinions-some strong, some weak; some we care deeply about, some we couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less. We often express those opinions to others and sometimes people agree, sometimes they don&amp;rsquo;t. Debating with others about our opinions helps us crystallise or completely discard them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am fairly opinionated about a lot of things and have debates about them with friends and co-workers. Yet when it comes to opinions on the Internet, I shy away. Every single day, I come across issues and incidents about which I have opinions and every time I stare at what somebody else wrote, consider replying and ultimately close the tab after a minute. This happens on almost all the Internet communities I frequent - Twitter, Guardian&amp;rsquo;s Comment is Free, Guardian&amp;rsquo;s Football blogs and Hacker News.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Tinfoil setup</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/17/my-tinfoil-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/17/my-tinfoil-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I try to be careful when I use the internet. This is not because I do illegal stuff—I just don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of random websites tracking me across the web, recording everything I do, and then serving me advertisements. I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of technocracies like Facebook collecting and storing data about me, even after I have explicitly quit their colourful walled garden. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t like Google tracking what websites I read by pretending to provide a service to the creators of those websites in the form of CDN and Analytics. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t want marketing optimisation services to track me and put me in their funnel, unless I explicitly want to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This means that when I browse the web, I treat cookies, javascript code and third party content with suspicion. Over the years, my setup has evolved in to something that makes my internet use safe, all the while being useful. These are some of the things I do to ensure that sites are not tracking me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Link titles were for the early adopters</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/11/when-link-titles-were-for-the-early-adopters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/11/when-link-titles-were-for-the-early-adopters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While doing some reading up on the comparative merits of using footnotes and hyperlinks in web pages, I came across an article &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from 1998 by Jakob Nielsen &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; about using the then nascent &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt; attribute on hyperlinks to inform users as to where clicking on a URL is going to take them. It is a very interesting read and makes passionate if not compelling arguments in favour of using the title attribute to improve the usability of a web page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is something interesting in the article that made me think about the evolution of the web. To quote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-adoption-of-link-titles-recommended&#34;&gt;Early Adoption of Link Titles Recommended&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Normally, I advise against using new Web technologies for the first year after they have been introduced. In most cases, using anything new is asking for trouble and will alienate users with older browsers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Link titles are an exception to the need to wait a year. First, their use does not hurt users with browsers that don&amp;rsquo;t display link titles (assuming you follow the guideline to keep the link anchor understandable when the link title is not displayed). Second, a browser that does not understand link titles will simply skip them. Since the title is not a new tag or otherwise intended to influence the layout of the page, the page will look exactly the same whether or not the browser does anything with the link titles. The only downside is that link titles will add approximately 0.1 seconds to the download time for a typical Web page over a modem connection. This is a rather harsh penalty, but worth paying because of the increased navigation usability for those users who do get to see the link titles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When URL shortening results in longer URLs</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/11/when-url-shortening-results-in-longer-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/11/when-url-shortening-results-in-longer-urls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have previously &lt;a href=&#34;https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/17/social-networks-and-url-shorteners/&#34;&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/23/dear-content-creator-your-url-shortener-is-pointless/&#34;&gt;how social networks&lt;/a&gt; use URL shortening as a way of obscuring and swallowing information about sharing of content on their platform. In Twitter&amp;rsquo;s case, this means that all URLs are automatically &amp;lsquo;shortened&amp;rsquo; with their &lt;em&gt;t.co&lt;/em&gt; domain. All their official clients take this shortening into account when you create a Tweet so as to avoid a round trip across the network to figure out if the tweet is short enough. But what happens if you are posting a URL that does not require any shortening? Something interesting happens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fusing the old media and the new</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/10/fusing-the-old-media-and-the-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/10/fusing-the-old-media-and-the-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Kara Swisher&amp;rsquo;s well written &lt;a href=&#34;http://allthingsd.com/20130807/dear-jeff-bezos-heres-what-i-saw-as-an-analog-nobody-in-the-mailroom-of-the-washington-post/?mod=thisweek&#34;&gt;open letter to Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt; in the light of the latter&amp;rsquo;s announcement that he has bought the Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To me, the most important trick is to deeply inculcate the joy of Internet journalism, without losing (actually restoring to some degree, after recent cutbacks) the great editorial values and breakthrough journalism of the Post. Fusing the old-media storytelling and news-integrity values that I learned at the Post with the Internet values of speed and personality — and, well, some level of fun at the right times — is critical.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In other words, make it clear that it is possible to do great journalism in an Internet way — even more possible because you’re freer and, most of all, readers want to read it that way. That entails inspiring the staffers of the newspaper to create content that is — as it has been — accurate, ethically sound, of high quality, but also much more compelling, and delivered in a way that modern customers want to consume it. Formulate those big stories primarily on the Web, and allow a conversation with readers to bubble up from there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet in Yemen : A Tale of Woe</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/08/internet-in-yemen-a-tale-of-woe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/08/08/internet-in-yemen-a-tale-of-woe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Haykal Bafana paints a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.haykal.sg/index.php/yemen1/20-ec/20-internet-in-yemen-a-tale-of-woe&#34;&gt;sad picture&lt;/a&gt; of the state of internet access in Yemen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each time a saboteur cuts the fiber optic lines in Marib, Internet access in Sanaa and even eastern Yemeni regions such as Hadhramaut are affected severely. Many have asked me before : why should a sparsely populated desert area like Marib be so critical to Yemen&amp;rsquo;s Internet service? A detour into the murky history of Yemeni telecommunications is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Android fragmentation -  It is not a bad thing</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/07/30/my-thoughts-on-android-fragmentation-it-is-not-a-bad-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/07/30/my-thoughts-on-android-fragmentation-it-is-not-a-bad-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OpenSignal released the July 2013 edition &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of their State of Android report. Among many things like the dominance of Samsung, HTC&amp;rsquo;s faltering performance and Motorola&amp;rsquo;s struggle, it points out that the Android device landscape is more fragmented than ever. Out of &lt;em&gt;682000&lt;/em&gt; devices surveyed for the report, &lt;em&gt;11868&lt;/em&gt; distinct devices were seen. This has met with cries of anguish from Developers and the usual suspects &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a very important point in the OpenSignal report that gets ignored or does not get as much focus as it deserves. To quote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For consumers, extreme fragmentation means that they can get exactly the phone they want – big or small, cheap or expensive, with any number of different feature combinations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dear Content Creator, Your URL Shortener Is Pointless</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/23/dear-content-creator-your-url-shortener-is-pointless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/23/dear-content-creator-your-url-shortener-is-pointless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People love URL shorteners. They are everywhere. You can use one of&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl&#34;&gt;the giants&lt;/a&gt;, or use one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly&#34;&gt;URL Shortening As A Service&lt;/a&gt; options available&#xA;or you can run one on your own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But none of that matters. Apart from adding to the redirect hell&#xA;prevalent on the web today and giving you a minor branding push, custom&#xA;URL shorteners does not add anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People started using these shortening services because of two&#xA;reasons. The first reason was the necessity to share&#xA;ugly URLs like&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/reports.php?start=2001&amp;amp;end=2010&amp;amp;item=Foo%20bar&#34;&gt;http://example.com/reports.php?start=2001&amp;amp;end=2010&amp;amp;item=Foo%20bar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and&#xA;they wanted to make it easier on the eyes of people. The second reason&#xA;was the limit on the number of characters allowed in a post by micro blogging services&#xA;like Twitter and Identi.ca.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am not on Facebook</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/11/why-i-am-not-on-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/11/why-i-am-not-on-facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday a colleague of mine asked me if I was on Facebook. He&#xA;was genuinely surprised by my reply that I was not and he wanted to know&#xA;why. For the next 20 minutes or so, I explained to him why I quit&#xA;Facebook and does not want anything to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time I have had to explain my absence from Facebook. In this post I will explain my attitude towards Facebook in a more structured manner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Broadly, these are the points I will touch upon:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Narcissism&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Symmetric nature of sharing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The social pressure to &amp;lsquo;friend&amp;rsquo; someone&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Low signal to noise ratio&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks and their URL Shorteners</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/17/social-networks-and-their-url-shorteners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/07/17/social-networks-and-their-url-shorteners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been noticing lately that much of the traffic that my blog&#xA;receives comes from Twitter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;t.co&lt;/strong&gt; domain or Google+&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;plus.url.google.com&lt;/strong&gt; domain. I don&amp;rsquo;t receive much traffic and I don&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;particularly care about the amount of traffic. However, when I&#xA;see traffic from Google+ or Twitter, I know that somebody is discussing&#xA;or sharing my posts and I am curious to know who is doing that. But if I&#xA;look at where the traffic comes from, with the hope that I will be able&#xA;to find Tweets or Google+ updates where people are talking about my&#xA;content, all I would be able to see is a &lt;strong&gt;t.co&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;plus.url.google.com&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;URL that redirects to my page. While it is mildly frustrating, I have&#xA;been thinking why both Twitter and Google+ replace every URL users share&#xA;on their network and replace it with their own URLs that does a redirect&#xA;to the original content being shared.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
