<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAS on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/tags/sas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAS on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2008-2025 Sadique Ali.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 19:46:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sadique.io/tags/sas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding trailing @ processing in SAS input</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2019/03/23/understanding-trailing-@-processing-in-sas-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 19:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2019/03/23/understanding-trailing-@-processing-in-sas-input/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I noticed when I started poking around in SAS code is that the &lt;code&gt;input&lt;/code&gt; statement is very powerful, flexible and hence sometimes hard to understand. It can read pretty much anything in to a dataset as long as you tell it what to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of trailing &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt;s to take control of how SAS advances the input pointer is a powerful technique to read from input files where the data is laid out in non-standard formats. In this blog post, we will try to understand how trailing &lt;code&gt;@&lt;/code&gt; processing works with the help of some &lt;code&gt;infile&lt;/code&gt; statement options and the &lt;code&gt;putlog&lt;/code&gt; statement to write to the SAS log.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importing the SASUSER datasets in SAS Studio</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2019/03/23/importing-the-sasuser-datasets-in-sas-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 18:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2019/03/23/importing-the-sasuser-datasets-in-sas-studio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been playing around with SAS for the last two weeks. I started with a SAS University Edition running on a VirtualBox instance on my MacBook, but soon realized that it was way more convenient to use a SAS OnDemand account. Having made the switch, I realized that all learning materials made references to and used examples with datsets from a library named &lt;code&gt;SASUSER&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was not clear how to get these datasets and use them in SAS Studio. After a bunch of searches, I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://communities.sas.com/t5/SAS-Certification/How-to-get-SASUSER-library-s-data-sets/m-p/306631/highlight/true#M124&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; that pointed at data set up scripts for these datasets. The URL it pointed to had of course been repurposed and now redirected to a marketing page. After going back through multiple versions of the page on Internet Archive, I finally managed to find a &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20151005165134/http://support.sas.com:80/publishing/cert/basecertguide3.html&#34;&gt;snapshot&lt;/a&gt; that linked to a set up file that worked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
