<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 19:44:03 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sdqali.in/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Net::HTTP and the simplest of explanations</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2018/03/21/nethttp-and-the-simplest-of-explanations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 19:44:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2018/03/21/nethttp-and-the-simplest-of-explanations/</guid>
      <description>This blog post exists purely to remind myself that Ruby&amp;rsquo;s Net::HTTP expects a host and a port as parameters when creating a new connection and not a url string.
This is a story about how many layers of abstractions and indirections one works through on a daily basis as a developer and the effort required to dive through these layers, all the while ignoring the simplest of explanations of why things may have gone wrong in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python URL manipulation revisited</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2017/09/25/python-url-manipulation-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 21:22:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2017/09/25/python-url-manipulation-revisited/</guid>
      <description>My last blog post about publishing standalone files to Nexus repositories prompted me to revisit URL manipulation in Python. When I did this the last time, I used Python stand library&amp;rsquo;s urlparse and it did the job. This time around, I needed to do a different kind of manipulation. Given a URL, I had to set credentials on it.
I started at urlparse and soon realized that Python3 moved this module to urllib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading a standalone artifact to Nexus 3</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2017/08/17/uploading-a-standalone-artifact-to-nexus-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 21:00:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2017/08/17/uploading-a-standalone-artifact-to-nexus-3/</guid>
      <description>This is one of those &amp;ldquo;I had to figure out how to do this today, so the next time I google this, I have a place to look&amp;rdquo; blog posts. Today, I had to upload a zip file as a build artifact to our Nexus 3 repository. The zip file had been generated by custom shell scripts that did not have a Maven, Ivy or Gradle projects to wrap them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing feature toggles for a Spring Boot application - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/29/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 22:50:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/29/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the fourth part of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/series/feature-toggles/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; about implementing &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/21/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-1/&#34;&gt;feature toggles&lt;/a&gt; for a Spring Boot application, we will take a look at how our implementation so far introduced a dependency on the application being restarted for changes to take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing feature toggles for a Spring Boot application - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/28/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 22:50:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/28/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the third part of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/series/feature-toggles/&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; about implementing feature toggles for a Spring Boot application, we will take a look at exposing the state of feature flags as a Spring Boot management end point for monitoring and testing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing feature toggles for a Spring Boot application - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/26/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 22:48:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/26/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the second part of this [series](&amp;ldquo;/series/feature-toggles/&amp;rdquo;) about implementing feature toggles for a Spring Boot application, we will look at exposing the features to the Angular front-end so that features can be toggled in UI components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing feature toggles for a Spring Boot application - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/21/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 17:03:03 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/21/implementing-feature-toggles-for-a-spring-boot-application---part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one of our recent projects at work, we implemented feature toggles for a Spring MVC / Angular JS code base and this &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/series/feature-toggles&#34;&gt;series of blog posts&lt;/a&gt; discusses our motivations and requirements, the approach we took and what we learned from it.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a secure etcd cluster behind a proxy</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/11/setting-up-a-secure-etcd-cluster-behind-a-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 13:07:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/11/setting-up-a-secure-etcd-cluster-behind-a-proxy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post that explains how to set up a highly available etcd cluster behind a proxy and securing the communication between a client and the proxy, between the proxy and the individual member in the cluster and between members in the cluster.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very basic introduction to deploying a Java application using Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/04/a-very-basic-introduction-to-deploying-a-java-application-using-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 22:34:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/04/a-very-basic-introduction-to-deploying-a-java-application-using-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with Kubernetes and Docker lately. To borrow the description of Kubernetes from their website,
 &amp;ldquo;Kubernetes is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.&amp;rdquo;
 One of the first things I did was to try and see what it would take to go from an application to deploying it. I started with a simple Java application and had to set up the development environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Deserialization errors in Spring Redis Sessions</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/02/handling-deserialization-errors-in-spring-redis-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 13:10:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/11/02/handling-deserialization-errors-in-spring-redis-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges of using storing spring sessions in Redis is that the objects that gets stored as part of a session often undergoes changes as the application evolves and these changes cause de-serialization exceptions to be thrown after a deployment when a session created before the deployment is presented to the application. This blog post discusses a method to work around this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSRF Protection with Spring Security and Angular JS</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/20/csrf-protection-with-spring-security-and-angular-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 21:57:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/20/csrf-protection-with-spring-security-and-angular-js/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Both Spring Security and Angular JS provide support for CSRF protection. However, getting these to work together to provide protection from CSRF requires some non-obvious configuration. This blog post explains how to add CSRF protection to an application that uses Spring Security with an Angular JS front end.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Redis auto-configuration for Spring Boot Session</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/16/controlling-redis-auto-configuration-for-spring-boot-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 15:42:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/16/controlling-redis-auto-configuration-for-spring-boot-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been using Spring Boot, chances are that you are using the Spring Session library to handle sessions. Spring Session has the ability to persist the sessions to various data stores, including Redis. The default behaviors of Spring Boot when combined with Spring Session is to start using Redis as the session store the moment &lt;code&gt;spring-session-data-redis&lt;/code&gt; is detected in the class path, thereby making it hard to conditionally turn Redis support ON and OFF. This blog post explores why this is the default behavior and presents a solution to control this behavior.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWT authentication with Spring Web - Part 5</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/13/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 23:05:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/13/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In parts 1 through 4 of this series, we built a Spring API that can issue a JWT when a user successfully authenticates and verify the JWT presented by the client for subsequent requests. In this blog post - the last in the series, we will build a simple Angular JS application with authentication that uses this API as the backend.

These are the blog posts in this series:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWT authentication with Spring Web - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/07/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 23:47:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/07/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In parts 1 through 3 of this series, we built a Spring API that can issue a JWT when a user successfully authenticates. In this blog post, we will add the capability to verify the JWT presented by the client for subsequent requests.

These are the blog posts in this series:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWT authentication with Spring Web - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/05/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 22:30:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/05/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/03/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-2/&#34;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, we built the Spring API that responds with Profile information. Continuing on the path to building authentication with JWT, in this blog post, we will create a login mechanism that issues a JWT when the user presents the correct credentials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWT authentication with Spring Web - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/03/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 09:22:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/03/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/02/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-1/&#34;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt; in this series, we looked at the basics of JWT. We will move on to building the Spring API that we will use JWT for authentication in this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JWT authentication with Spring Web - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/02/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 18:42:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/07/02/jwt-authentication-with-spring-web---part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta content=&#34;jwt authentication example&#34; name=&#34;keywords&#34;&gt;
JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) are signed tokens issued by a server that it can use to verify a claim made by a client. This blog post is the first in a series where I implement authentication based on JWT in a Spring Web application with an Angular JS front end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSON logging for Spring applications</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/06/30/json-logging-for-spring-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 19:43:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/06/30/json-logging-for-spring-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta content=&#34;logstash spring boot example&#34; name=&#34;keywords&#34;&gt;
If you have an application that writes logs, there are many reasons to make it write the log in JSON format. It makes it easier to search and analyze them when using tools such as the ELK Stack &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. JSON formatted logs make it easier to look at them when looking at how the app is behaving in real time using tools like jq &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This blog post documents how to format logs as JSON in a Spring application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Injecting dependencies into a Spring @Configuration</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/06/28/injecting-dependencies-into-a-spring-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 23:17:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/06/28/injecting-dependencies-into-a-spring-configuration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of those blog posts about things I wish I had known before I spent a lot of time figuring out when something was not working as expected. Recently, we have been trying to extend a &lt;code&gt;WebMvcConfigurerAdapter&lt;/code&gt; to wire up an HTTP request interceptor. And things did not work as we expected it to and we learned that our understanding of how Spring behaved under this situation was wrong. This is a write up to refer back to if and when we encounter this issue again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtering responses in Spring MVC</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/06/08/filtering-responses-in-spring-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 13:23:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/06/08/filtering-responses-in-spring-mvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday my colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/imdhmd&#34;&gt;Imdad&lt;/a&gt; asked if there was a mechanism to add filtering to a Spring MVC end point that responded with JSON. We both started looking at it and this blog post explores a way to do it, albeit for a specific type of responses that was relevant to our discussions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Inverness</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/06/05/on-inverness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 14:08:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/06/05/on-inverness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, I was in the Scottish Highlands - soaking in the beauty of the city of Inverness, hiking through the South Loch Ness trail and traveling across the Black Isle. It was a wonderful trip - one that I wish was longer. This was a trip that invoked so many memories in me - among other things, of a man whose voice was part of growing up. A voice that traveled from the BBC Studios in the United Kingdom halfway across the globe and into a radio set in South Malabar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecating domain events in Axon</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/04/24/deprecating-domain-events-in-axon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 18:35:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/04/24/deprecating-domain-events-in-axon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently at work, we had to deprecate a domain event. This event used to represent an error scenario. However, the business had since decided that this is no longer a valid error scenario. Removing the Java class is not straight forward - since there are events of this type stored in the event store, every time the aggregate associated with this event is loaded, Axon will throw errors trying to de-serialize them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmable exit codes for spring command line applications - 2</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/04/19/programmable-exit-codes-for-spring-command-line-applications---2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 22:29:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/04/19/programmable-exit-codes-for-spring-command-line-applications---2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/04/17/programmable-exit-codes-for-spring-command-line-applications/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, we took a look at how to implement programmable exit codes for spring command line applications by using exceptions that implement &lt;code&gt;ExitCodeGenerator&lt;/code&gt;. This time, we will take a look at how to achieve the same without having to depend on an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmable exit codes for Spring command line applications</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/04/17/programmable-exit-codes-for-spring-command-line-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 23:36:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/04/17/programmable-exit-codes-for-spring-command-line-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spring&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;CommandLineRunner&lt;/code&gt; provides a great mechanism to build command line applications. While this convenience is great, applications that use &lt;code&gt;CommandLineRunner&lt;/code&gt; require extra effort in some areas like integration testing. Exit codes are such an area - applications that use command line runners always report their exit code as &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; even if there are exceptions thrown. This blog post explains a way to get to programmable exit codes for such applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using custom arguments in Spring MVC controllers</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/01/29/using-custom-arguments-in-spring-mvc-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 17:41:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2016/01/29/using-custom-arguments-in-spring-mvc-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta content=&#34;spring, arguments, handlermethodargumentresolver, spring mvc, spring boot&#34; name=&#34;keywords&#34;&gt;
Most of the Spring controllers in the real world accept a lot of different types of parameters - Path variables, URL parameters, request headers, request body and sometimes even the entire HTTP Request object. This provides a flexible mechanism to create APIs. Spring is really good at parsing these parameters in to Java types as long as there is an ObjectMapper (like Jackson) configured to take care of the de-serialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are situations where you want methods to receive a parameter of a particular type that has to resolved from a set of parametersâ€“for example, an API can expect consumers to send meta data about a request in the form of headers and need a custom type to hold this information. Spring provides a convenient way to provide such custom arguments. This blog post explores this feature and how to implement it and test it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication for Apache Camel HTTP components</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/16/authentication-for-apache-camel-http-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 01:07:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/16/authentication-for-apache-camel-http-components/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My team at work has been lately working on a data transformer that pushes information from an external system in to platform. For historical reasons the information is passed to us in the form of flat files. We have been working on a data transformer that reads information from the file and posts it into an HTTP end point.
Apache Camel &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; makes a natural choice as the base for implementing such a data transformer. The presence of ready to use components that can read files and post information to HTTP end points and the availability of a nice D.S.L. &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; makes implementation easy and straightforward. One of the things we had to spend time figuring out was how to ensure that we authenticate correctly against our target HTTP end point. This blog post takes a look at various methods we explored.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Open Graph tags</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/14/thoughts-on-open-graph-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 21:47:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/14/thoughts-on-open-graph-tags/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Open Graph protocol was designed by Facebook to help content creators generate a richer preview of links to their content when they get posted in to Facebook. It was originally proposed as a simple mark up that can be adopted in platforms beyond Facebook. The Open Graph Protocol Design Decisions presentation &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; does a very good job of enumerating the motivation and design decisions made for Open Graph. I have lately been reading and experimenting with these tags and I notice a fair bit of differences when it comes to how these tags are used by different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration testing Spring command line applications</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/11/integration-testing-spring-command-line-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 15:57:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/11/integration-testing-spring-command-line-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/10/integration-testing-challenges-for-non-web-spring-applications/&#34;&gt;last blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about the challenges of writing an integration test for a Spring command line application. One of the solutions for this issue discussed in the blog post was to use the &lt;code&gt;@IntegrationTest&lt;/code&gt; annotations to inject Java system properties and use that to run the application instead of the normal command line arguments. This blog post describes how to perform this.

The first step is to rewrite our test to use the &lt;code&gt;@IntegrationTest&lt;/code&gt; annotations. This will result in a test that looks as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration testing challenges for non-web Spring applications</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/10/integration-testing-challenges-for-non-web-spring-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 21:45:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/10/integration-testing-challenges-for-non-web-spring-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are building a command line data loader application at work that uses Spring. One of the things that I took us more time that it should have to figure out was how to write an integration test that invokes the command line application with the right command line arguments. This blog post describes this scenario and a potential solution to this problem.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How thinking of Documentation as Legislation helped me become a better programmer</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/07/how-thinking-of-documentation-as-legislation-helped-me-become-a-better-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 20:43:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/07/how-thinking-of-documentation-as-legislation-helped-me-become-a-better-programmer/</guid>
      <description>When I first started programming, it was predominantly creating applications that utilized the C++ graphics library. I was 14 and my friends and I tried to make the most of the time we got to spend at the computer lab of the boarding school we attended. We created applications that drew pretty, often animated pictures on the screen and not much else. This taught us basics, but our learning lacked any kind of structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing custom annotations for Spring MVC</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/06/implementing-custom-annotations-for-spring-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 13:28:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/06/implementing-custom-annotations-for-spring-mvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta content=&#34;spring, annotation, custom annotation, spring mvc, spring boot&#34; name=&#34;keywords&#34;&gt;
I often have to work with Spring MVC based code bases that have been living for a while. One of the common trait of these code bases I have observed is the repeated use of the same Spring annotations to achieve the same effect again and again. A really good example of this is annotating a controller method with a combination of &lt;code&gt;@RequestMapping&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;@ResponseStatus&lt;/code&gt; to set the expected request and response &lt;code&gt;Content-Type&lt;/code&gt;, the request Method, response status etc. This blog post describes how to create custom Spring annotationshow to create custom annotation in spring mvc that produce the same effect as multiple Spring annotations acting together.

Among the new things introduced in Spring 4 was the idea of meta-annotations. &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Meta annotations are annotations that can act up on other annotations by modifying and overriding attributes of the target annotations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating RequestParams and PathVariables in Spring MVC</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/04/validating-requestparams-and-pathvariables-in-spring-mvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 22:50:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/12/04/validating-requestparams-and-pathvariables-in-spring-mvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta content=&#34;spring, validate, request, parameters, @requestparam, spring mvc, param, validation&#34; name=&#34;keywords&#34;&gt;
Spring MVC provides a convenient way to validate inputs to API end points through the use of &lt;code&gt;JSR-303&lt;/code&gt; annotations. While this mechanism works great for end points that consume a &lt;code&gt;RequestBody&lt;/code&gt; (as is the case with most &lt;code&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;PUT&lt;/code&gt; requests), it is not easy to achieve the same effect for end points that consume primitives in the form of path variables or request parameters (as is the case with most &lt;code&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; requests).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing async responses using MockMvc</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/11/24/testing-async-responses-using-mockmvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 05:45:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/11/24/testing-async-responses-using-mockmvc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are times when a Spring MVC end point performs asynchronous operations. Testing these end points using MockMvc can be tricky because of the asynchronous nature in which the result of the operation is eventually returned. This blog post describes how to write tests in such scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running multiple applications in the same Tomcat installation</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/06/09/running-multiple-applications-in-the-same-tomcat-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 01:11:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/06/09/running-multiple-applications-in-the-same-tomcat-installation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post describes how to set up Tomcat to run multiple applications running as separate JVM processes, using the same Tomcat installation. This method utilizes the &lt;code&gt;CATALINA_HOME&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;CATALINA_BASE&lt;/code&gt; environment variables used by Tomcat. I have verified this method against Tomcat versions &lt;code&gt;8.0.x&lt;/code&gt;; other versions should work the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of Cloud Foundry security group declarations</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/05/21/making-sense-of-cloud-foundry-security-group-declarations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 22:58:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/05/21/making-sense-of-cloud-foundry-security-group-declarations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud Foundry allows fine grained declaration of security groups, down to IP address ranges and Ports. While this provides great flexibility, making sense of why each rule in a security group exists and what each does is really difficult because of the limitations of the security group declaration mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Cloud Foundry Java Memory Parameters</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/05/20/configuring-cloud-foundry-java-memory-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 19:42:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2015/05/20/configuring-cloud-foundry-java-memory-parameters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I have been trying out Cloud Foundry. Today while trying to set up monitoring through AppDynamics, the sample application that I was using started crashing because of a Java memory error. This blog post discusses how to prevent this from happening by configuring Java memory parameters used by the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disputed territories and merging shapes and features</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/08/08/disputed-territories-and-merging-shapes-and-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/08/08/disputed-territories-and-merging-shapes-and-features/</guid>
      <description>Making a map that shows a disputed territory can be a tricky business. Nation states vigorously contest maps that appear to portray a boundary that challenges what a border looks like. From the Falkland Islands to Kuril Islands; from Western Sahara to Arunachal Pradesh, disputed territories result in omissions, additions and inaccuracies in maps.
I grew up looking at maps in books printed by the Oxford Press, that came with a disclaimer in blue rubber stamped across them that stated how the map was wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A list of GIS tools</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/08/03/a-list-of-gis-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/08/03/a-list-of-gis-tools/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with maps a lot these days and have ended up using various tools in the process. This blog post is a way to make a note of these tools for later use.
geojson.io Mapbox&amp;rsquo;s geojson.io is a simple tool for creating, editing and sharing maps. It lets you import map data in various formats and has an editor to modify maps.
GeoJSON-TopoJSON Jeff Paine&amp;rsquo;s GeoJSON-TopoJSON is a simple tool to convert between the more common GeoJSON format and the TopoJSON format used by libraries like D3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing the Yelp dataset into MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/08/02/importing-the-yelp-dataset-into-mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/08/02/importing-the-yelp-dataset-into-mongodb/</guid>
      <description>Today Yelp announced their dataset challenge 1. The dataset they released includes data from 5 cities (Phoenix, Las Vegas, Madison, Waterloo and Edinburgh) and consists of
 42,153 businesses 320,002 business attributes 31,617 check-in sets 252,898 users 955,999 edge social graph 403,210 tips 1,125,458 reviews  The data is available for public consumption, although Yelp owns any derivative dataset you create from the original 2.
The data is available as files with each line representing a JSON object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure Dojo - Levenshtein edit distance</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/03/20/clojure-dojo---levenshtein-edit-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/03/20/clojure-dojo---levenshtein-edit-distance/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with Clojure and after familiarising myself with the core, I decided to start writing little programs that forces me to choose the right idioms. I am starting off with Levenshtein edit distance of two strings.
Levenshtein edit distance Levenshtein edit distance between two string is a way of quantifying how similar or dissimilar they are, lower distance implying higher similarity. The algorithm to calculate Levenshtein distance is fairly simple - the algorithm cares about three operations that can be performed at a particular position in a string to move it towards the other - insertion, deletion and substitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple JMeter test with login</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/02/17/a-simple-jmeter-test-with-login/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/02/17/a-simple-jmeter-test-with-login/</guid>
      <description>I had to set up a JMeter test last week - the test included logging in to a site, and then hitting a bunch of URLs, all of them being GET requests. I found it hard to find a simple documentation that described how to do this - the ones I found were either incomplete or were trying to teach me a large number of things at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SNDP - NSS political experiment of 1980s</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/02/09/the-sndp---nss-political-experiment-of-1980s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2014/02/09/the-sndp---nss-political-experiment-of-1980s/</guid>
      <description>Last week, at the annual congregation of the Sree Narayana Dharma Paripalana (S.N.D.P.) Yogam, it&amp;rsquo;s leaders - Vellaapalli Nadesan and his son Thushaar announced that the Yogam is about to form their own political party that will unite Hindus of Kerala under one umbrella. 1 S.N.D.P. and it&amp;rsquo;s leaders are no strangers to threatening to announce their intent to form a political party. 2 They did the same in 2012, generating much talk in Kerala&amp;rsquo;s political landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is life?</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/12/10/what-is-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/12/10/what-is-life/</guid>
      <description>Life is the heap of broken pieces of crayons adjacent to that heap of broken pieces of your heart, laying by the heap of bills eclipsing the heap of paychecks and all that was lost while you were busy working hard to create those piles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A rainy distraction</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/11/21/a-rainy-distraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/11/21/a-rainy-distraction/</guid>
      <description>Far away, the Sutro TV tower was hardly visible in the haze of rain.
&amp;ldquo;So, this is what you were talking about in the morning? I thought it was the other calculation. You are right!&amp;rdquo;. You suddenly feel happy and detect the smugness creeping to your face. I was right, I told you so, you want to say. But you don&amp;rsquo;t. &amp;ldquo;Not today! The smugness will have to die.&amp;rdquo;
As the thick rain drops fall on your naked torso, causing that ever so little note of pain that you have come to like and seek, you roll the muddy football under your feet and look up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fear of being wrong on the Internet</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/15/the-fear-of-being-wrong-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/15/the-fear-of-being-wrong-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>All of us have opinions-some strong, some weak; some we care deeply about, some we couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less. We often express those opinions to others and sometimes people agree, sometimes they don&amp;rsquo;t. Debating with others about our opinions helps us crystallise or completely discard them.
I am fairly opinionated about a lot of things and have debates about them with friends and co-workers. Yet when it comes to opinions on the Internet, I shy away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Rate Limiting in Rails - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/13/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails---part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/13/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails---part-2/</guid>
      <description>The first part of this series can be found here.
The first part of this series looked at how to implement basic rate limiting in a Rails application. However, as pointed out in the improvements section, the implementation was not complete - it did not provide clients enough information about the rate limiting that is in place and how long they should wait before making further requests once they hit the limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Rate Limiting in Rails - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/12/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/12/implementing-rate-limiting-in-rails---part-1/</guid>
      <description>The second part of this series can be found here.
Rate limiting or throttling is the practice of limiting how frequently legitimate users of a web service can access the service. Rate limiting is often put in place to prevent the hogging of resources by a sub set of the users of the system. Rate limiting works by responding with error messages when a client exceeds their allocated share of requests within a predefined time window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Hack - Dynamically override an object&#39;s attribute</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/07/python-hack---dynamically-override-an-objects-attribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/07/python-hack---dynamically-override-an-objects-attribute/</guid>
      <description>While working with Locust 1 recently, we ran into a situation where we had to dynamically override an attribute in a class in the Locust library so as to control what value it got assigned. After a lot of scratching our heads and reading the Python documentation, we came across the property function. We were able to use this to hack together a solution that ensures that every time an attribute is read, it returns the result of executing a method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting an Image in to a Canvas object</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/03/fitting-an-image-in-to-a-canvas-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/03/fitting-an-image-in-to-a-canvas-object/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with Canvas objects and images for a side project I am doing. One of the first things I had to figure out for this project was how to fit an image of arbitrary height and width on to a Canvas object of arbitrary, but known dimensions while preserving the aspect ratios of the image. This blog post is an explanation of the solution I came up with for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Environment Variables in Gradle</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/01/accessing-environment-variables-in-gradle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/01/accessing-environment-variables-in-gradle/</guid>
      <description>I have been writing a fun Android App. Share With Title is a small application that allows you to share web pages you are reading to other applications without having to jump through the messy copy-paste hoop. (You should try it. If you share stuff from the web like I do, it will save you a lot of time and frustration). I have been coding on Android Studio, Google&amp;rsquo;s IntelliJ based IDE for Android development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading user input in Gradle scripts</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/01/reading-user-input-in-gradle-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/01/reading-user-input-in-gradle-scripts/</guid>
      <description>Continuing from the last blog post, I have been looking at reading user input from a Gradle script. This was a result of Stack Overflow user user672009&amp;rsquo;s question about prompting for input from a Gradle script so the one does not have to include passwords in the script while checking in.
Just like the last example, the fact that Gradle scripts are written in a Groovy DSL comes to our help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby, Named Capture Groups and Local Variables</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/01/ruby-named-capture-groups-and-local-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/10/01/ruby-named-capture-groups-and-local-variables/</guid>
      <description>Ruby&amp;rsquo;s regular expressions support named capture groups, since 1.9. However, there is a weird behaviour while using named capture groups with the Regexp#=~ method. When named capture groups are used with =~, the captured values are placed in local variables with the same name as the capture group. The following example demonstrates this:
#!/usr/bin/env ruby month = &amp;#34;January&amp;#34; test_string = &amp;#34;Today&amp;#39;s date is: 9/28/2013.&amp;#34; /(?&amp;lt;month&amp;gt;\d{1,2})\/(?&amp;lt;day&amp;gt;\d{1,2})\/(?&amp;lt;year&amp;gt;\d{4})/ =~ test_string puts month.inspect This when executed will print 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Named Capture Groups in Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/29/named-capture-groups-in-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/29/named-capture-groups-in-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>I will admit that I find regular expressions somewhat hard to parse. While the thinking process needed to write a regular expression is iterative and hence results in the correct expression suitable for the situation, once it is written it lacks readability. I have faced that pain of trying to grok a complex regular expression written years ago. So I was pleasantly surprised when I saw this example from Hacker News user WestCoastJustin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decomposing URLs in Python</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/26/decomposing-urls-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/26/decomposing-urls-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Python&amp;rsquo;s urlparse module breaks down URLs in to components. It supports all the URL schemes specified in RFC 3986 1.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import urlparse &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; urlparse.urlparse(&amp;#34;https://example.com/foo?param=bar&amp;#34;) ParseResult(scheme=&amp;#39;https&amp;#39;, netloc=&amp;#39;example.com&amp;#39;, path=&amp;#39;/foo&amp;#39;, params=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;, query=&amp;#39;param=bar&amp;#39;, fragment=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; urlparse.urlparse(&amp;#34;file://example.com/etc/fstab&amp;#34;) ParseResult(scheme=&amp;#39;file&amp;#39;, netloc=&amp;#39;example.com&amp;#39;, path=&amp;#39;/etc/fstab&amp;#39;, params=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;, query=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;, fragment=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; urlparse.urlparse(&amp;#34;news:comp.infosystems.www.misc&amp;#34;) ParseResult(scheme=&amp;#39;news&amp;#39;, netloc=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;, path=&amp;#39;comp.infosystems.www.misc&amp;#39;, params=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;, query=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;, fragment=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;) IETF - RFC for Uniform Resource Identifier (URI): Generic Syntax. [return]   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Halal Burgers</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/17/on-halal-burgers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/17/on-halal-burgers/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What would you like to have today?&amp;rdquo; The lady at the counter cheerfully asks. I smile back at her, take another cursory glance at the menu and with a sigh say &amp;ldquo;I will take the Teriyaki Salmon Sandwich, please!&amp;rdquo;. I take another look at all the menu and can&amp;rsquo;t help notice how sad I am. The assortment of meat preparations bundled between two pieces of bread that could have been mine is long and diverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared history in Bash</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/15/shared-history-in-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/15/shared-history-in-bash/</guid>
      <description>One of the features that I miss most in Bash is the shared history between terminals that Zsh supports. I was hunting down a solution for this and came across this Stack Overflow answer 1 by user lesmana. This code snippet does the trick:
HISTSIZE=9000 HISTFILESIZE=$HISTSIZE HISTCONTROL=ignorespace:ignoredups history() { _bash_history_sync builtin history &amp;#34;$@&amp;#34; } _bash_history_sync() { builtin history -a #1  HISTFILESIZE=$HISTSIZE #2  builtin history -c #3  builtin history -r #4 } PROMPT_COMMAND=&amp;#34;_bash_history_sync;$PROMPT_COMMAND&amp;#34; This is very hackyâ€”This setting overrides the shell prompt to sync history every time the prompt is loaded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Gemsets in Rbenv</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/12/managing-gemsets-in-rbenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/12/managing-gemsets-in-rbenv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was setting up my new laptop today, I decided to use Rbenv &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to manage my Ruby versions. I have typically used RVM &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and had never used Rbenv. Rbenv is a Ruby version manager written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sstephenson/&#34;&gt;Sam Stephenson&lt;/a&gt; and deliberately tries to do less and do it well. Instead of overriding Bash commands like RVM does, Rbenv chooses to use wrappers or &lt;strong&gt;shims&lt;/strong&gt; around Ruby binaries to choose the Ruby executable to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works well, until you have to manage Gemsets &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Often, one is working on two projects that use the same version of Ruby, but has entirely different chain of dependency on Gems. RVM&amp;rsquo;s gemsets work really well for this use case. I was looking around to see how one would manage gemsets with Rbenv. There are three ways to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking up Compiler params used to compile a Ruby version</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/08/looking-up-compiler-params-used-to-compile-a-ruby-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/09/08/looking-up-compiler-params-used-to-compile-a-ruby-version/</guid>
      <description>Today Kashyap asked how one can identify the compiler parameters passed when compiling a Ruby version. I was curious how to achieve this and like any confused developer started searching for and looking in the Ruby documentation. Searching for compiler parameters in ruby did not yield any interesting results and the group of constants with the RUBY_ prefix 1 loaded in Ruby did not include anything related to compiler flags. Then I came across this blog post 2 by Jan Lelis and I was curious what else RbConfig::CONFIG contains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Stacktraces in Emacs</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/22/navigating-stacktraces-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/22/navigating-stacktraces-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had to debug an issue today and that meant dealing with Rails stack traces. I got tired of having to constantly switch between reading the trace in the terminal and the code in Emacs to figure out what was going wrong and get more context around it. I felt that there should be an easier way of doing this. A quick search &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; did not yield anything. But then I remembered Grep mode &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and it occurred to me that hijacking Grep mode&amp;rsquo;s navigation feature would let me navigate the stack trace better. This is the solution I came up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief History of Times New Roman</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/21/a-brief-history-of-times-new-roman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/21/a-brief-history-of-times-new-roman/</guid>
      <description>Mathew Butterick&amp;rsquo;s Practical Typography 1 features a section dedicated to the History of Times New Roman 2. It is an interesting read.
 Why not? Fame has a dark side. When Times New Roman appears in a book, document, or advertisement, it connotes apathy. It says, â€œI submitted to the font of least resistance.â€ Times New Roman is not a font choice so much as the absence of a font choice, like the blackness of deep space is not a colour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Tinfoil setup</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/17/my-tinfoil-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/17/my-tinfoil-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I try to be careful when I use the internet. This is not because I do illegal stuffâ€”I just don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of random websites tracking me across the web, recording everything I do, and then serving me advertisements. I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of technocracies like Facebook collecting and storing data about me, even after I have explicitly quit their colourful walled garden. &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t like Google tracking what websites I read by pretending to provide a service to the creators of those websites in the form of CDN and Analytics. &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t want marketing optimisation services to track me and put me in their funnel, unless I explicitly want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that when I browse the web, I treat cookies, javascript code and third party content with suspicion. Over the years, my setup has evolved in to something that makes my internet use safe, all the while being useful. These are some of the things I do to ensure that sites are not tracking me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python&#39;s bool type</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/15/pythons-bool-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/15/pythons-bool-type/</guid>
      <description>Python does not have a true boolean type. The True and False built-in values in Python are wrappers around the integers 1 and 0. This results in some interesting results involving True and False.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; True == 1 True &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; False == 0 True &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; True + 9 10 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; False - 1 -1 &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; str(True) &amp;#39;True&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; repr(True) &amp;#39;True&amp;#39; The Python bool implementation got formalised in PEP 285 1 in 2002 by Guido van Rossum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Link titles were for the early adopters</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/11/when-link-titles-were-for-the-early-adopters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/11/when-link-titles-were-for-the-early-adopters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While doing some reading up on the comparative merits of using footnotes and hyperlinks in web pages, I came across an article &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from 1998 by Jakob Nielsen &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; about using the then nascent &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;em&gt;title&lt;/em&gt; attribute on hyperlinks to inform users as to where clicking on a URL is going to take them. It is a very interesting read and makes passionate if not compelling arguments in favour of using the title attribute to improve the usability of a web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something interesting in the article that made me think about the evolution of the web. To quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-adoption-of-link-titles-recommended&#34;&gt;Early Adoption of Link Titles Recommended&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, I advise against using new Web technologies for the first year after they have been introduced. In most cases, using anything new is asking for trouble and will alienate users with older browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link titles are an exception to the need to wait a year. First, their use does not hurt users with browsers that don&amp;rsquo;t display link titles (assuming you follow the guideline to keep the link anchor understandable when the link title is not displayed). Second, a browser that does not understand link titles will simply skip them. Since the title is not a new tag or otherwise intended to influence the layout of the page, the page will look exactly the same whether or not the browser does anything with the link titles. The only downside is that link titles will add approximately 0.1 seconds to the download time for a typical Web page over a modem connection. This is a rather harsh penalty, but worth paying because of the increased navigation usability for those users who do get to see the link titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When URL shortening results in longer URLs</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/11/when-url-shortening-results-in-longer-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/11/when-url-shortening-results-in-longer-urls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have previously &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/17/social-networks-and-url-shorteners/&#34;&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/23/dear-content-creator-your-url-shortener-is-pointless/&#34;&gt;how social networks&lt;/a&gt; use URL shortening as a way of obscuring and swallowing information about sharing of content on their platform. In Twitter&amp;rsquo;s case, this means that all URLs are automatically &amp;lsquo;shortened&amp;rsquo; with their &lt;em&gt;t.co&lt;/em&gt; domain. All their official clients take this shortening into account when you create a Tweet so as to avoid a round trip across the network to figure out if the tweet is short enough. But what happens if you are posting a URL that does not require any shortening? Something interesting happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fusing the old media and the new</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/10/fusing-the-old-media-and-the-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/10/fusing-the-old-media-and-the-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Kara Swisher&amp;rsquo;s well written &lt;a href=&#34;http://allthingsd.com/20130807/dear-jeff-bezos-heres-what-i-saw-as-an-analog-nobody-in-the-mailroom-of-the-washington-post/?mod=thisweek&#34;&gt;open letter to Jeff Bezos&lt;/a&gt; in the light of the latter&amp;rsquo;s announcement that he has bought the Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, the most important trick is to deeply inculcate the joy of Internet journalism, without losing (actually restoring to some degree, after recent cutbacks) the great editorial values and breakthrough journalism of the Post. Fusing the old-media storytelling and news-integrity values that I learned at the Post with the Internet values of speed and personality â€” and, well, some level of fun at the right times â€” is critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, make it clear that it is possible to do great journalism in an Internet way â€” even more possible because youâ€™re freer and, most of all, readers want to read it that way. That entails inspiring the staffers of the newspaper to create content that is â€” as it has been â€” accurate, ethically sound, of high quality, but also much more compelling, and delivered in a way that modern customers want to consume it. Formulate those big stories primarily on the Web, and allow a conversation with readers to bubble up from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biriyani and me</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/09/biriyani-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/09/biriyani-and-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Biriyani. That is an understatement. I absolutely love Biriyani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started when I was very young. In fact, as far back as I can remember, I have loved Biriyani. A lot of people in my family - my father, a paternal uncle and his wife were cooks, and specialists in cooking for special occasions. In Malabar, that meant people employed them to cook at weddings, engagements, &lt;em&gt;Iftars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Parasavathinu Kontu Pokals&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mudikalachils&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. They would cook up a storm of Biryani, &lt;em&gt;Neychor&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Porotta&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pathiri&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and curries of beef, chicken and mutton. Of all these things, the Biriyanis were the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet in Yemen : A Tale of Woe</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/08/internet-in-yemen--a-tale-of-woe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/08/internet-in-yemen--a-tale-of-woe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Haykal Bafana paints a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.haykal.sg/index.php/yemen1/20-ec/20-internet-in-yemen-a-tale-of-woe&#34;&gt;sad picture&lt;/a&gt; of the state of internet access in Yemen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each time a saboteur cuts the fiber optic lines in Marib, Internet access in Sanaa and even eastern Yemeni regions such as Hadhramaut are affected severely. Many have asked me before : why should a sparsely populated desert area like Marib be so critical to Yemen&amp;rsquo;s Internet service? A detour into the murky history of Yemeni telecommunications is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph databases 1 - Modeling</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/02/graph-databases-1---modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/08/02/graph-databases-1---modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am making my way through the book &lt;em&gt;Graph Databases&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which is an introductory book to the subject from Neo Technology &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, creators of Neo4j &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. At work, we are using Neo4j for a cool new thing we are building, and I see it as a great chance to learn some thing new and interesting. In the past, I have gone through a spiral &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; when it comes to learning stuff and the constant feedback I get is to pick something that one gets to work with everyday and dig deep into it, in order to avoid the frustration and the inevitable spiral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating JSON in Emacs</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/07/31/validating-json-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/07/31/validating-json-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta content=&#34;validate&#34; name=&#34;keywords&#34;&gt;
At work, I have to deal with Amazon CloudFormation &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; templates a fair bit. These templates are JSON files. More and more members of our team are moving away from TextMate to Emacs which makes me really happy. We would like to validate these CloudFormation templates in Emacs. Today we set this up and I hope this turns out to be of help to some one else trying to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Android fragmentation -  It is not a bad thing</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/07/30/my-thoughts-on-android-fragmentation----it-is-not-a-bad-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/07/30/my-thoughts-on-android-fragmentation----it-is-not-a-bad-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OpenSignal released the July 2013 edition &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of their State of Android report. Among many things like the dominance of Samsung, HTC&amp;rsquo;s faltering performance and Motorola&amp;rsquo;s struggle, it points out that the Android device landscape is more fragmented than ever. Out of &lt;em&gt;682000&lt;/em&gt; devices surveyed for the report, &lt;em&gt;11868&lt;/em&gt; distinct devices were seen. This has met with cries of anguish from Developers and the usual suspects &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a very important point in the OpenSignal report that gets ignored or does not get as much focus as it deserves. To quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For consumers, extreme fragmentation means that they can get exactly the phone they want â€“ big or small, cheap or expensive, with any number of different feature combinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>à´®à´´à´¯àµà´Ÿàµ† à´“àµ¼à´®àµà´®à´•àµ¾</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/07/24/%E0%B4%AE%E0%B4%B4%E0%B4%AF%E0%B5%81%E0%B4%9F%E0%B5%86-%E0%B4%93%E0%B5%BC%E0%B4%AE%E0%B5%8D%E0%B4%AE%E0%B4%95%E0%B5%BE/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/07/24/%E0%B4%AE%E0%B4%B4%E0%B4%AF%E0%B5%81%E0%B4%9F%E0%B5%86-%E0%B4%93%E0%B5%BC%E0%B4%AE%E0%B5%8D%E0%B4%AE%E0%B4%95%E0%B5%BE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;à´•àµŠà´Ÿ à´Žà´Ÿàµà´¤àµà´¤à´¿à´Ÿàµà´Ÿàµ à´ªàµ‹&amp;rdquo; à´“à´Ÿà´¿àµ» à´ªà´¾à´¤àµà´¤à´¿à´•à´³à´¿àµ½ à´¨à´¿à´¨àµà´¨àµ à´†à´¦àµà´¯à´¤àµà´¤àµ† à´®à´´à´¤àµà´¤àµà´³àµà´³à´¿ à´¦àµ‡à´¹à´¤àµà´¤àµ à´µàµ€à´´àµà´¨àµà´¨à´¤à´¿à´¨àµ à´¤àµŠà´Ÿàµà´Ÿàµ à´®àµàµ»à´ªàµ à´‰à´®àµà´®à´¯àµà´Ÿàµ† à´¶à´¬àµà´¦à´‚ à´•àµ†à´Ÿàµà´Ÿàµ à´ªàµà´±à´•à´¿àµ½. à´‡à´žà´¿à´ªàµà´ªàµŠ à´…à´¤à´¿à´¨àµŠà´¨àµà´¨àµà´‚ à´¨àµ‡à´°à´²àµà´²à´¾à´¨àµà´¨àµ à´žà´¾à´¨àµà´‚. à´®à´´ à´¨à´¨àµà´¨à´¾à´¯à´¿ à´•àµ‹à´°à´¿à´šàµà´šàµŠà´°à´¿à´¯àµà´¨àµà´¨àµ. à´…à´°à´¯à´¿àµ½ à´®à´Ÿà´•àµà´•à´¿à´•àµà´•àµà´¤àµà´¤à´¿à´¯ à´ªàµà´³àµà´³à´¿à´¤àµà´¤àµà´£à´¿ à´…à´¯à´žàµ à´¤àµâ€à´Ÿà´™à´¿ à´Žà´¨àµà´¨àµŠà´°àµ à´ªàµ‡à´Ÿà´¿. à´®à´Ÿà´¿à´¯à´¿àµ½ à´ªàµŠà´¤à´¿à´žàµà´žàµ à´µà´šàµà´š à´®àµŠà´¬àµˆàµ½à´«àµ‹à´£àµà´‚ à´ªàµ‡à´´àµâ€à´¸àµà´‚ à´•àµ‡à´Ÿàµ à´µà´¨àµà´¨à´¾à´²àµ‹ à´Žà´¨àµà´¨ à´ªàµ‡à´Ÿà´¿ à´®à´¨à´¸àµà´¸à´¿àµ½ à´•àµà´Ÿà´¿à´¯à´¿à´°à´¿à´•àµà´•àµà´¨àµà´¨à´¤à´¿à´¨àµ à´®àµàµ»à´ªàµ‡ à´•àµ‡à´´à´•àµà´•àµ‹à´±à´¤àµà´¤àµ† à´šàµ†à´±à´¿à´¯ à´µà´¾à´¤à´¿àµ½ à´ªà´¾à´³à´¿à´•à´³à´¿à´²àµà´²à´¾à´¤àµà´¤ à´—àµ‡à´¯àµà´±àµà´±àµà´‚ à´•à´Ÿà´¨àµà´¨àµ à´µàµ‡â€à´³àµà´³à´®àµŠà´²à´¿à´•àµà´•àµà´•àµà´•àµà´¨àµà´¨ à´Žà´Ÿàµ‡à´¯à´¿à´²àµ†à´¤àµà´¤à´¿à´ªàµà´ªàµ‹à´¯à´¿. à´‡à´žàµà´žà´¿à´ªàµà´ªàµŠ à´¨àµ‹à´•àµà´•àµ€à´±àµà´±àµ à´•à´¾à´°àµà´¯à´²àµà´². à´ªàµ‡à´´àµâ€à´¸àµà´‚ à´®àµŠà´¬àµˆà´²àµà´‚ à´’à´¨àµà´¨àµà´‚ à´•àµ‚à´Ÿà´¿ à´†à´žàµà´žàµ à´®à´Ÿà´•àµà´•à´¿ à´ªàµâ€à´³àµà´³à´¿à´¤àµà´¤àµà´£à´¿ à´’à´¨àµà´¨àµ à´®àµà´±àµà´•àµà´•à´¿. à´¨àµ†â€à´°à´¿à´¯à´¾à´£à´¿ à´µà´°àµ† à´µàµ†à´³àµà´³à´®àµà´£àµà´Ÿàµâ€Œ à´Žà´Ÿàµ‡à´¯à´¿à´²àµ. à´®à´´ à´®àµ‹à´¤àµà´¤àµ à´…à´Ÿà´¿à´•àµà´•à´¾àµ» à´¤àµà´Ÿà´™àµà´™à´¿. à´•à´±àµà´¤àµà´¤ à´ªàµàµ¾àµ¾ à´“à´µà´±à´¿àµ»à´Ÿàµ† à´¹àµà´¡àµ à´Žà´Ÿàµà´¤àµà´¤àµ à´¤à´²à´•àµà´•àµ à´®àµ‡à´²àµ‡à´•àµà´•àµ à´µà´²à´¿à´šàµà´šàµ. à´ªàµâ€à´³àµà´³à´¿à´¤àµà´¤àµà´£à´¿à´¯àµà´‚ à´ªàµàµ¾àµ¾ à´“à´µà´±àµà´‚.à´šà´¿à´¨àµà´¤à´¿à´•àµà´•à´¾àµ» à´•à´¿à´Ÿàµà´Ÿàµà´¨àµà´¨ à´¸à´®à´¯à´¤àµà´¤à´¿à´¨àµà´±àµ† à´µà´²àµà´²àµà´¯ à´ªà´™àµà´•àµà´‚ à´šàµ†à´²à´µà´¾à´•àµà´•à´¿à´ªàµà´ªàµ‹à´°àµà´¨àµà´¨ à´† à´µà´¿à´šà´¾à´°à´¤àµà´¤à´¿à´²àµ‡à´•àµà´•àµ à´¤à´¨àµà´¨àµ† à´šàµ†à´¨àµà´¨àµ†à´¤àµà´¤à´¿ à´®à´¨à´¸àµà´¸àµ. à´‡à´µà´¿à´Ÿàµ†à´¯àµà´‚ à´…à´µà´¿à´Ÿàµ†à´¯àµà´®à´²àµà´²à´¾à´¤àµ†, à´•àµ†à´´à´•àµà´•àµà´‚ à´ªâ€à´Ÿà´¿à´žàµà´žàµà´žà´¾à´°àµà´®à´²àµà´²à´¾à´¤àµ†, à´ˆ à´—àµà´°à´¾à´®à´¤àµà´¤à´¿à´²àµ‹ à´•à´Ÿà´²à´¿à´¨à´Ÿàµà´¤àµà´¤ à´µàµ» à´¨à´—à´°à´¤àµà´¤à´¿à´²àµ‹ à´…à´²àµà´²à´¾à´¤àµ†.  à´žà´¾àµ» à´Žà´µà´¿à´Ÿàµà´¤àµà´¤àµâ€Œà´•à´¾à´°à´¨à´¾? à´–àµ½à´¬à´¿à´²àµ†à´µà´¿à´ŸàµŠà´¯àµŠà´•àµà´•àµ†à´¯àµ‹ à´’à´°àµ à´¨àµ€à´±àµà´±àµ½.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireworks in the paddy fields - memories of a summer</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/05/27/fireworks-in-the-paddy-fields---memories-of-a-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/05/27/fireworks-in-the-paddy-fields---memories-of-a-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like most people, I like certain songs for their ability to bring back memories of times, places and people from the past that you don&amp;rsquo;t everyday bring out from the cellars of time, wipe away the cobwebs and dust and gaze at. &lt;em&gt;Kannu Nattu Kaathirunnittum&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from the movie &lt;em&gt;Kathaavasheshan&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; evokes memories of childhood, the daily struggle to survive and the inability to resist the hegemony of those around you who call the shots. But, there are not many songs that does it for me quite like the Malayalam song &lt;em&gt;Alliyaambal Kadavil&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs hack: Viewing Git logs while composing commit messages</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/29/emacs-hack-viewing-git-logs-while-composing-commit-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/29/emacs-hack-viewing-git-logs-while-composing-commit-messages/</guid>
      <description>I use Emacs as my editor to compose Git commit messages. I almost never commit from the terminal with git commit -m. This approach has two advantages: I get a chance to verify what is being committed and get to compose the message using a proper editor complete with spell checking provided by flyspell mode. One thing I wish I had access to while composing commit messages is the git log.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Git&#39;s comment character</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/14/configure-gits-comment-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/14/configure-gits-comment-character/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR - Use the core.commentchar configuration to change the character Git uses to mark comment lines in commit messages.
My team has a convention of putting the number of the current Issue/Ticket/Story that we are working on at the beginning of every commit message. This is great because it lets us make sense of the history of our code by helping us answer
 What were the changes made to the code base to build a feature or fix an issue?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My experience working remotely</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/11/my-experience-working-remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/11/my-experience-working-remotely/</guid>
      <description>There has been a lot of debate in the tech community about working remotely and the willingness of employers to allow this option to their employees. At the very beginning of my career as a programmer, I had the opportunity to work on a distributed team. While the team was distributed, I was still working from an office and for almost half of the duration of my work on the team I had team members sitting beside me in the same office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh I can build it in...</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/08/oh-i-can-build-it-in.../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/08/oh-i-can-build-it-in.../</guid>
      <description>Oh, is this what you guys have been building for three years? I can build it in a month!
 Substitute the two time durations with something appropriate and you end up with how some software developers react after encountering a new project or application. I have seen this happen in multiple situations, where I had more context of how the application in question had evolved which the person making the comment did not have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript, clipboard access and hidden flash widgets</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/05/javascript-clipboard-access-and-hidden-flash-widgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/04/05/javascript-clipboard-access-and-hidden-flash-widgets/</guid>
      <description>Letting users copy text and URLs from a webpage effortlessly is one of those things that sound easy in theory, but is a pain when it comes to implementation. Browsers take great efforts to ensure that web pages are sand boxed in such a way that a web application can not read from or write to the system&amp;rsquo;s clipboard without jumping through hoops. Firefox asks you to change browser configurations to give web applications access to the system clipboard, while Internet Explorer shows a modal dialog to confirm that you really want to allow the application access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Emacs startup time while committing</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/01/22/reducing-emacs-startup-time-while-committing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/01/22/reducing-emacs-startup-time-while-committing/</guid>
      <description>I use Emacs as my primary text editor and I use it to edit commit messages for Git. I almost never use the -m option with git commit. Since I have a fairly customised Emacs configuration based around Sam Aaron&amp;rsquo;s Emacs Live, this means that for every commit, there is a visible delay for Emacs to start up for the commit message. I was looking for ways to reduce this and figured out that running Emacs in daemon mode and using emacsclient as the GIT_EDITOR would solve this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First week in San Francisco</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/01/21/first-week-in-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/01/21/first-week-in-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>I moved to San Francisco last week and is just getting acquainted with the city. This blog post is a summary of my first impressions of SF to share with a lot of friends whom I have not been able to keep in touch and who have been wondering what I am up to.
It is cold here I landed in SF without enough winter wear. I had a windbreaker that I used in Bangalore and provided more than adequate warmth back in Bangalore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2012</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/01/02/books-read-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2013/01/02/books-read-in-2012/</guid>
      <description>              Sadique Ali&#39;s favorite books Â» Share book reviews and ratings with Sadique, and even join a book club on Goodreads.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Firefox plugin: GetCache - View cached version of the current page</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/29/my-first-firefox-plugin-getcache---view-cached-version-of-the-current-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/29/my-first-firefox-plugin-getcache---view-cached-version-of-the-current-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I released my &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/getcache-ff/&#34;&gt;first Firefox plugin&lt;/a&gt; today. It
is awaiting review, but if you are adventurous, you can install it right
now. Go on, try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I had written the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/28/getcache-a-chrome-plugin-to-view-cached-version-of-the-current-page/&#34;&gt;Chrome version&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ManishChaks&#34;&gt;Manish&lt;/a&gt; suggested
that I should write one for Firefox. There already exist Firfox plugins
that does exactly what GetCache does, but I decided to go ahead and write it
for fun. And of course, the fact that I could publish it without having
to sign up with my Credit Card information was enticing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GetCache - A Chrome plugin to view cached version of the current page</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/28/getcache---a-chrome-plugin-to-view-cached-version-of-the-current-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/28/getcache---a-chrome-plugin-to-view-cached-version-of-the-current-page/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the plugin
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/downloads/GetCache.crx&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On numerous occasions, I have ran in to the situation where I had to
look up how to load Google&amp;rsquo;s cached version of a particular page. This
happens often when I follow a link from Hacker News or Reddit to a blog
post and the blog has went down due to the great avalanche of traffic
from HN and Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After struggling to remember and having to Google how to get the cached
version, I decided to finally solve this issue. I wrote &lt;code&gt;GetCache&lt;/code&gt;, a
dead simple Google Chrome plugin that loads Google&amp;rsquo;s cached version of
the current page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing&#34;&gt;Installing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the plugin
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/downloads/GetCache.crx&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In order to install it, open your
Extensions page (&lt;code&gt;Window -&amp;gt; Extensions&lt;/code&gt;) and drag the downloaded &lt;code&gt;CRX&lt;/code&gt;
file to the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On REST, Content-Type, Google Chrome and Caching</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/27/on-rest-content-type-google-chrome-and-caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/27/on-rest-content-type-google-chrome-and-caching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Representational State Transfer (REST) is a style of software
architecture for distributed systems that has replaced technologies like
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SOAP&#34;&gt;SOAP&lt;/a&gt; as the predominant Web service
design model. Originally proposed by Roy Fielding in his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ics.uci.edu/~fielding/pubs/dissertation/rest_arch_style.htm&#34;&gt;Doctorate
dissertation&lt;/a&gt;,
REST puts a lot of emphasis on resources, their representations and states. Basically a URL indicates a
single resource; the HTTP method (GET, POST, PUT, DELETE) indicates what
action should be performed on that resource; and the ACCEPT header indicates the format that the resource should be presented in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chrome-and-content-type&#34;&gt;Chrome and Content-Type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having seen this, one would assume that if you have a resource, say a
&lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; on your system and there were two representations of that
resource - HTML and JSON. Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that the HTML representation does
an AJAX call to fetch the JSON representation and renders it. While this
sounds simple enough, Google Chrome, one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular
browsers
&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=108766&#34;&gt;totally breaks this&lt;/a&gt;. A
good example of this weird behaviour can be seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrome-json-bug.heroku.com/docs&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.

I ran in to this issue while playing around with &lt;a href=&#34;http://expressjs.com/&#34;&gt;Express JS&lt;/a&gt;.
Now, the interesting thing here is that the Chrome developers seem to
have closed the issue without providing any convincing answers or
indicating whether they would fix this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Browsers Detect If You Are Offline</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/22/how-browsers-detect-if-you-are-offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/11/22/how-browsers-detect-if-you-are-offline/</guid>
      <description>When I saw the newly released Heyoffline.js library, I was curious to see how it figured out if the user was online or not. This led me to the window.navigator.onLine API and how different browsers implement it. Chrome, Safari and Inernet Explorer 10 make sure that the API detects if the user is connected to a network, while Firefox changes this flag if and only if the user chooses the Work Offline option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Content Creator, Your URL Shortener Is Pointless</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/23/dear-content-creator-your-url-shortener-is-pointless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/23/dear-content-creator-your-url-shortener-is-pointless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People love URL shorteners. They are everywhere. You can use one of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl&#34;&gt;the giants&lt;/a&gt;, or use one of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly&#34;&gt;URL Shortening As A Service&lt;/a&gt; options available
or you can run one on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But none of that matters. Apart from adding to the redirect hell
prevalent on the web today and giving you a minor branding push, custom
URL shorteners does not add anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People started using these shortening services because of two
reasons. The first reason was the necessity to share
ugly URLs like
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.com/reports.php?start=2001&amp;amp;end=2010&amp;amp;item=Foo%20bar&#34;&gt;http://example.com/reports.php?start=2001&amp;amp;end=2010&amp;amp;item=Foo%20bar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and
they wanted to make it easier on the eyes of people. The second reason
was the limit on the number of characters allowed in a post by micro blogging services
like Twitter and Identi.ca.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving up the Samba for the Tiki-taka</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/21/giving-up-the-samba-for-the-tiki-taka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/21/giving-up-the-samba-for-the-tiki-taka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A shot flew over the bar. The goal keeper showed great urgency in
collecting the ball from behind the goal. Instead of kicking it forward, he pushed the ball
gently out to the centre back. As the opposition forward streamed
forward to close him down, the defender moved the ball swiftly and pushed it to
the right back who was level with the penalty box. Another push and the
central mid fielder was brought in to the play. A through ball to the
left found the player on the left wing and as the opposing
right back zoomed in to focus, he played it back to his left back. As
the left back controlled the ball, his
team repositioned themselves to start from scratch all over again. To build
from the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have watched football in the recent past, you would recognise a
pattern here. You would see the unmistakable Barcelona blueprint. Except
that I am not describing Barcelona. Not even Spain. In fact when the
initial shot flew over the bar, there was no collective sigh of relief
from a crowd [packed till the heavens](&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mkbarcelona.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/200311-005.jpg&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;http://mkbarcelona.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/200311-005.jpg&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;),
there was no eager ball boy to throw the ball back at the keeper and
there was no one in the dug out shouting instructions at the
players. Hell, there was not even a dug out near the touch line. The
keeper ran to the construction site where the ball had found it&amp;rsquo;s way
through and ran back all the way to get the play restarted. As he was
still was running back, the left back of my opponents walked back to his
position, his face embellished with a smile bore out of his pride
of having bent his shot around the cashew tree inside the
ground.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curse of the Community Shield?</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/15/curse-of-the-community-shield/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/15/curse-of-the-community-shield/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Click on the image to see the visualisation:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sdqali.in/visualizations/community_shield/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sdqali.in/images/community_shield.png&#34; alt=&#34;Community Shield visualisation&#34; title=&#34;Community Shield Visualisation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The football season in Europe began this weekend with countries hosting
their equivalents of the &lt;em&gt;Super Cup&lt;/em&gt;. For those confused as to what a
super cup, the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Super_cup&#34;&gt;Wikipedia entry&lt;/a&gt; is a good
starting point. Super cups, at least in European national
leagues are curtain-raisers for the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FA &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FA_Community_Shield&#34;&gt;Community Shield&lt;/a&gt;
is England&amp;rsquo;s Super Cup and it pits the winners of the FA Cup against the
winners of the Premier League from the previous season. This year&amp;rsquo;s game saw Manchester City
beat Chelsea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning the Community Shield at the beginning of the
season is considered a bad omen by a lot of football fans - an indicator that the team who win it
would not win the subsequent league season. This supposed curse is
widely discussed in
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redcafe.net/f6/curse-community-shield-165424/&#34;&gt;fan forums&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2005/jan/26/theknowledge.sport&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt;. And
what would be complete on the Internet without a &lt;a href=&#34;http://9gag.com/gag/5030472&#34;&gt;dinosaur thinking
aloud&lt;/a&gt; about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I am not on Facebook</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/11/why-i-am-not-on-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/11/why-i-am-not-on-facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday a colleague of mine asked me if I was on Facebook. He
was genuinely surprised by my reply that I was not and he wanted to know
 why. For the next 20 minutes or so, I explained to him why I quit
 Facebook and does not want anything to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time I have had to explain my absence from Facebook. In this post I will explain my attitude towards Facebook in a more structured manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broadly, these are the points I will touch upon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Narcissism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symmetric nature of sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The social pressure to &amp;lsquo;friend&amp;rsquo; someone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low signal to noise ratio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3.js Workshop</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/01/d3.js-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/08/01/d3.js-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did a &lt;a href=&#34;http://d3js.org&#34;&gt;d3.js&lt;/a&gt; workshop at ThoughtWorks Bangalore yesterday (31st
July, 2012). I split the workshop in to two parts. The first was a basic
introduction to d3.js - SVG, Scaling, Axes etc. The second part
was an exercise to hack together a Scatterplot with some Cricket
dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 30 people attended the workshop. I spent too much time on the first part and hence we did not have enough
time to complete the second part. This was the first ever workshop I have done
and my time plan was way off. I should fix it the next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualisation - How European clubs dominate their leagues</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/21/visualisation---how-european-clubs-dominate-their-leagues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/21/visualisation---how-european-clubs-dominate-their-leagues/</guid>
      <description>Click here to see the visualisation.
This is a visualization showing how various European football clubs have dominated their respective national leagues over various time periods. The visualization shows data for England, France, Germany, Italy, Netherlands and Spain.
The visualization is self-explanatory. You can choose a league to view from the dropdown and then choose the sliders to select an era for which you want to look at the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks and their URL Shorteners</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/17/social-networks-and-their-url-shorteners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/17/social-networks-and-their-url-shorteners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been noticing lately that much of the traffic that my blog
receives comes from Twitter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;t.co&lt;/strong&gt; domain or Google+&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;strong&gt;plus.url.google.com&lt;/strong&gt; domain. I don&amp;rsquo;t receive much traffic and I don&amp;rsquo;t
particularly care about the amount of traffic. However, when I
see traffic from Google+ or Twitter, I know that somebody is discussing
or sharing my posts and I am curious to know who is doing that. But if I
look at where the traffic comes from, with the hope that I will be able
to find Tweets or Google+ updates where people are talking about my
content, all I would be able to see is a &lt;strong&gt;t.co&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;plus.url.google.com&lt;/strong&gt;
URL that redirects to my page. While it is mildly frustrating, I have
been thinking why both Twitter and Google+ replace every URL users share
on their network and replace it with their own URLs that does a redirect
to the original content being shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XConf 6 - Data, My Heart!</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/16/xconf-6---data-my-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/16/xconf-6---data-my-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday,  Srijayanth Sridhar (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/craftybones&#34;&gt;@craftybones&lt;/a&gt;) and I gave a talk at XConf, ThoughtWorks India&amp;rsquo;s internal conference series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about visualising data, and the various visualisations that one could use to answer questions about the dataset you have. We looked at two particular datasets -  one showing the consumption of juice at the fresh juice counter in office and one about Indian and Pakistani players. We looked at various visualizations like Area charts, Box Plots, Chord Diagrams, Line Charts, Pie Charts, Donut Charts, Small Multiples, Spark Lines, Stack Charts and Treemaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Python&#39;s &#34;with&#34; statement</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/09/understanding-pythons-with-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/09/understanding-pythons-with-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-it&#34;&gt;What is it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; statement provides a very convenient way of dealing with the situation where you have to do a setup and teardown to make something happen. A very good example for this is the situation where you want to gain a handler to a file, read data from the file and the close the file handler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without the &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; statement, one would write something along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f0f3f3;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/tmp/foo.txt&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
data &lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;read()
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;close()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two annoying things here. First, you end up forgetting to close the file handler. The second is how to handle exceptions that may occur once the file handler has been obtained. One could write something like this to get around this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f0f3f3;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/tmp/foo.txt&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#069;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;try&lt;/span&gt;:
    data &lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;read()
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#069;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;finally&lt;/span&gt;:
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;close()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this works well, it is unnecessarily verbose. This is where &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; is useful. The good thing about &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; apart from the better syntax is that it is very good handling exceptions. The above code would look like this, when using &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f0f3f3;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#069;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/tmp/foo.txt&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#069;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;:
   data &lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#366&#34;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#555&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;read()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heredocs in Ruby and Python</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/04/heredocs-in-ruby-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/07/04/heredocs-in-ruby-and-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been doing some coding in Python recently. While playing around with some code, I noticed that the way &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Here_document&#34;&gt;heredocs&lt;/a&gt; are used in Python is different from Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the following snippet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f0f3f3;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#09f;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;# test.py&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#069;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;some text in single line&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#069;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;As opposed to
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;some text
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;written as
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;heredoc
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#069;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c30&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;and then another single line&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When run, this would result in this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f0f3f3;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;bash-3.2$ python test.py
some text in single line

As opposed to
some text
written as
heredoc

and &lt;span style=&#34;color:#069;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; another single line&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how there is a preceding and trailing linebreak around the string printed using heredoc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro Journal - simple Git-backed journal in Python</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/06/25/micro-journal---simple-git-backed-journal-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/06/25/micro-journal---simple-git-backed-journal-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Today, I pushed out Microjournal, a simple and lightweight journal. I wrote Microjournal to reduce the pain of typing a number of commands to create and maintain my daily journal which I type out in Emacs and use Git to store. It is a single file Python script.
Microjournal does not do much on it&amp;rsquo;s own. It creates a Git repository for you, and then you can write down entries whenever you feel like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VodQA NCR: Maintaining Large Test Suites</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/06/24/vodqa-ncr-maintaining-large-test-suites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/06/24/vodqa-ncr-maintaining-large-test-suites/</guid>
      <description>Srijayanth Sridhar and I did a talk yesterday at vodQA NCR.
The talk was about what makes maintenance of large test suites a pain and the things that have worked for us and we have seen work for other teams.
It went well and we got a lot of good feedback from the crowd. The prezi for the talk is below:
.prezi-player { width: 550px; } .prezi-player-links { text-align: center; }Maintaining Large Test Suites on Prezi</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Tools - Don&#39;t Shoot Yourself in the Foot</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/06/06/know-your-tools---dont-shoot-yourself-in-the-foot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/06/06/know-your-tools---dont-shoot-yourself-in-the-foot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine this - Your build is taking forever. You put in a lot of effort and restructure it. Things improve a lot, but it is far from where you would like it to be. You try hard to identify things that could improve the build time, but fail. You blame the platforms you use, you blame Ruby and you even blame the relative position of the Moon to Venus. Slowly you learn to accept the slow build as a part of your life. Months later a new developer joins the team and proves that there is a bug in the build scripts that causes certain tasks to be run twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened to us recently, and the subsequent debugging/postmortem revealed that there were things about our tools that we simply did not know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing security certificates from the console - on Windows, Mac OS X and Linux</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/06/05/managing-security-certificates-from-the-console---on-windows-mac-os-x-and-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/06/05/managing-security-certificates-from-the-console---on-windows-mac-os-x-and-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For me the last two weeks or so have involved a lot of wrestling with SSL certificates. One of the things that took some time to figure out was how to piggy-back on the tools provided by different Operating Systems to manage certificates. We did not want to rewrite &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/projects/security/pki/nss/&#34; title=&#34;NSS&#34;&gt;NSS&lt;/a&gt;. Luckily for us, all the major OSes provide tools to manage certificates from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spiral of Learning</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/05/30/the-spiral-of-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/05/30/the-spiral-of-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An hour ago, I was staring at a problem on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.4clojure.com/&#34; title=&#34;4clojure&#34;&gt;4clojure&lt;/a&gt; website. Last weekend, I found myself wandering through Zed Shaw&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://c.learncodethehardway.org/&#34; title=&#34;Learn C The Hard Way&#34;&gt;Learn C the Hard Way&lt;/a&gt;. Three days before that, I was taking a stab at figuring what kind of visualizations would make sense if you want to come up with the mother of all comparison&amp;rsquo;s between two of football&amp;rsquo;s greatest ever players. Four days before that, I was looking at some classifiers. Five weeks ago, I was totally lost in &lt;a href=&#34;http://learnyousomeerlang.com/&#34; title=&#34;Learn You Some Erlang For Great Good&#34;&gt;Learn You Some Erlang&lt;/a&gt;, and three weeks before that I was trying to make sense of all the hype around Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Crash and then You Learn</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/05/29/you-crash-and-then-you-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/05/29/you-crash-and-then-you-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I picked up my bicycle, climbed on it and spotted the blood on my elbows and the bunch of curious onlookers in front of the pan shop nearby, I did not feel fear or embarrassment. I had an immeasurable amount of happiness welling inside me. I had finally done what I should have about 20 years ago - I had finally managed to crash my bicycle and leave with plenty of scars to show for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am 25, and until two weeks ago I could not ride a bicycle. Two weeks ago, during a Saturday afternoon, I got on a bicycle and rode it around a football field. Well, what is so special about that, you might ask. It was pretty special to me because it was the first time I had rode a bicycle, where my definition of &amp;lsquo;ride&amp;rsquo; is &amp;lsquo;ride with a level of confidence that removes the fear on falling down!&amp;rsquo;. When it finally happened, it was like what Kevin Garnett &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3_gL_H9zAY8&#34;&gt;described&lt;/a&gt; when he finally won an NBA with the Celtics after years of disappointment with the Minnesota Timberwolves - &amp;ldquo;I Just Knocked the Bully Out&amp;rdquo;. Yes, I was emotional. No, I did not cry. But it had been a long time coming, and the journey was painful. Here is the story of me learning to cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian and Pakistani cricketers - who make better debuts?</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/05/11/indian-and-pakistani-cricketers---who-make-better-debuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/05/11/indian-and-pakistani-cricketers---who-make-better-debuts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently a friend and I had an argument about who makes better debuts among Indian and Pakistani cricket players. Now, I am not into cricket. But I do watch the odd matches here and there and am generally aware of what is going on in the game. My stand was that Pakistani players make better debuts compared to Indian players, while my friend was adamant that Indian players make better debuts. My friend is more of a cricket guy than I ever was and he asked me what is the basis of my stand. It was just a gut feel for me and I had to leave it as there was no way for me to prove that my gut feel was correct. But I did want to try, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to see if I could prove my theory. Luckily, Cricinfo has all this data, although they dont make it easy for you to get it. I wrote some scripts to pull this data and decided to visualise this using the awesome d3 library. In the end, this became more about figuring out d3 than winning the argument, but doing this was fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Flyspell for Emacs in Mac OS X</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/05/04/fixing-flyspell-for-emacs-in-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/05/04/fixing-flyspell-for-emacs-in-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I use the flyspell-mode as a spell checking mechanism in emacs. Recently, I moved to Mac OS X, and I began to get this error whenever I started emacs:
Error enabling Flyspell mode: (Searching for program No such file or directory aspell) I had installed aspell with Homebrew. The issue seemed to be that Emacs was unable to find the aspell binary. Homebrew installs binaries in /usr/local/bin and it was in my $PATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding un-merged commits with git cherry</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/04/29/finding-un-merged-commits-with-git-cherry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/04/29/finding-un-merged-commits-with-git-cherry/</guid>
      <description>In a project that I was a part of in the recent past, we used Story Branching. While it afforded us flexibility in pulling and pushing stories in and out of releases, it has given us some scares in the past. Somebody makes commits against a story, but the commit does not get merged to the correct release branch where it is supposed to go or gets merged to another release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bullet proof Jenkins setup</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/02/03/bullet-proof-jenkins-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/02/03/bullet-proof-jenkins-setup/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will describe how a neat setup and some discipline will ensure a Jenkins that can be rolled back and recreated very easily - a bullet proof Jenkins setup.
I have been working on configuring our Jenkins instance. This was the first time I had played around with Jenkins. I am fairly comfortable with Go from ThoughtWorks Studios. All of my past teams used Go as their tool for continuous delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why your project should have a Getting Started guide.</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/01/17/why-your-project-should-have-a-getting-started-guide./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/01/17/why-your-project-should-have-a-getting-started-guide./</guid>
      <description>My new team at work is writing a bunch of Rails applications. This is one of those codebases that one would call &#34;legacy&#34; without much argument. Most of these apps have their own patched, vendorized Rails versions.
Getting up and running was an absolute pain. This project existed before Bundler and the list of gem dependencies are not checked in. I got the output of running gem list on a colleague&#39;s box, wrote a Ruby script to generate a shell script that installs all the gems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging: C Sharp&#39;s HttpWebRequest, 100-Continue and nginx</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/01/16/debugging-c-sharps-httpwebrequest-100-continue-and-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2012/01/16/debugging-c-sharps-httpwebrequest-100-continue-and-nginx/</guid>
      <description>Recently I spent some time debugging an issue our team was facing around some C# code making a request on one of our servers. The request was throwing a &#34;The server committed a protocol violation. Section=ResponseStatusLine&#34; error.
Initial investigation suggested that this could happen if we are making HTTP/1.1 requests to a server configured for HTTP/1.0. Our Rails application runs on Mongrel fronted with nginx 0.6.5. We modified the C# code to use HTTP/1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banyan Tree: Football and Politics</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/12/05/banyan-tree-football-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/12/05/banyan-tree-football-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>I recently did a talk on football and the politics behind it, as part of the Banyan Tree talk series at ThoughtWorks. The slides from the talk can be found here on Speakerdeck.
It was great fun for me. I thought I did well. It is a topic I know my way around. The history behind the El Clasico - the Spanish civil war, Franco, the trade unions and Di Stefano was discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia Page Hopping</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/05/17/wikipedia-page-hopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/05/17/wikipedia-page-hopping/</guid>
      <description>I have realized that like most users of Wikipedia, I do a lot of Wikipedia page-hopping [1]. Wikipedia is sort of addictive that way. You start reading about a piece of Flamenco music and after twenty minutes find yourself staring at the page about ETA, a Basque nationalist organization. So I decided to figure out how I exactly do I get lost in the huge list of interconnected articles. I use Chromium, and it stores its history in a SQLite3 database file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/05/05/friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/05/05/friday/</guid>
      <description>The intense, almost mystical sound of the second set of prayers wafted through the air, following him through the wind, as if they did not want him to walk away from them. Just a shade of the thought of someone caring for him made him feel strangely happy. For a second. Soon the rational part of his brain kicked in. How much could the fast dispersing sound of prayers really care about him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poorly executed xkcd spoof</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/03/30/poorly-executed-xkcd-spoof/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/03/30/poorly-executed-xkcd-spoof/</guid>
      <description>There is not anything to add, except it is a poorly executed attempt to spoof xkcd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy Log Parser</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/03/24/empathy-log-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/03/24/empathy-log-parser/</guid>
      <description>I use Empathy as my preferred IM application. Today, I wanted to have a look at an IM conversation I had with someone. I pulled out the Empathy log corresponding to that conversation, and boom - it is in XML.
Just another excuse to write code. So I came up with the following. It was easy to write and it does not do much - It uses the Hpricot gem to parse the XML and prints the name of the people involved in the chat and their messages in a human readable form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Signature Art</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/03/23/binary-signature-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2011/03/23/binary-signature-art/</guid>
      <description>I was reading this very interesting thread on the xkcd forum when I noticed a post from a user with the following signature in binary:
01001101 01100001 01100100 01100101 00100000 01011001 01101111 01110101 00100000 01001100 01101111 01101111 01101011 00100001&amp;#34; At first, that did not particularly entice me, mostly because the topic being discussed was really interesting, but it did come back to my focus when I saw that another user had quoted the signature, along with the comment Yeah, you know it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying Good Bye is tough</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/05/10/saying-good-bye-is-tough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/05/10/saying-good-bye-is-tough/</guid>
      <description>Njaan Varaam, Assalamu Alaikum (I will be back, Peace Be Upon You). I felt myself choking as those words escaped my mouth. And as I reached the gate and took my first step out, I heard my mother say Wa Alaikum Assalaam (Peace Be Upon You, too). And then I felt the straps of the laptop bag sink into my shoulders, and it felt so heavy. It should not be. It still had the same stuff as it did when I set on my journey home on the Friday evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Arrays in JRuby</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/03/16/java-arrays-in-jruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/03/16/java-arrays-in-jruby/</guid>
      <description>Recently my team encountered a frustrating thing while working with a Java library in JRuby. It took us long to figure out what was going wrong. This is an attempt to write down what was happening.
You are in Ruby world, a world of weak typing, no type casting and pure bliss in coding. You forget that some languages care about the type of elements in an Array. And you end up spending a lot of time figuring out why you are staring at a stupid looking exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Athletic - The European campaign and a Basque special</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/02/06/athletic---the-european-campaign-and-a-basque-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/02/06/athletic---the-european-campaign-and-a-basque-special/</guid>
      <description>The last time I wrote about Athletic, they were relinquishing at the bottom of the La Liga table, their record as one among the only three clubs in La Liga to have never got relegated in threat.
More than a year later, things are really looking up at The Catedral. They managed to finish at seventh in the La Liga last season, qualifying for the Europa Liga. They are flying in Europa Liga this season, they are almost on the verge of breaking into the European qualifying positions again, they have one of La Liga&amp;rsquo;s most promising youngsters in Iker Muniain, and in typical Basque tradition, they are going to play in the knockout matches in Europe with &amp;lsquo;Euskadi&amp;rsquo; proudly written in front of their shirts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing the game</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/02/05/missing-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/02/05/missing-the-game/</guid>
      <description>I have continued to watch and follow the beautiful game, save for my first few months in Bangalore. This is supposed to be a metro. Well, apparently a metro where people don&amp;rsquo;t give a damn about football. After taking a cable connection, I soon realized that I will have to beg with the cable guy to put on ESPNStar so that I could watch EPL. Pretty soon, Hathway had some issues with ESPNStar, which meant there was no way I could watch ESPNStar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autorun.py - Execute stuff on file change</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/01/09/autorun.py---execute-stuff-on-file-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2010/01/09/autorun.py---execute-stuff-on-file-change/</guid>
      <description>I really liked ZenTest&amp;rsquo;s Autospec in action. Recently, when I was trying to write some Python stuff, I thought it would be nice if I would have a tool that would just run the unit tests, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to switch between console windows. Better still, I could run it from inside my Emacs.
Clearly, monitoring files for changes, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be big deal. I decided to write the tool myself in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TWU Graduation</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/09/22/twu-graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/09/22/twu-graduation/</guid>
      <description>As I had predicted, the last week of training was hectic, chaotic and crazy. Although we ended up leaving the whole project simulation in jeopardy, we learned a lot of things, especially how things that work smoothly at one second can go wrong very very wrong the next second.
I had decided beforehand that I would volunteer for roles that I want to do in my career, and that at the same time would leave me out of my comfort zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lot to learn</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/08/21/a-lot-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/08/21/a-lot-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>The past few days have just flown by. I had to learn so much things and did not have much time to do it. Most days, I sleep around 2:00 in the morning.
When I was in college, I had friends who were already working. I used to wonder why sometimes they did not reply to a mail I sent, or did not ping me back when I pinged them on IM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another week in Bangalore</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/08/16/yet-another-week-in-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/08/16/yet-another-week-in-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>Yet another week of my Bangalore life has unfolded. It was tougher, and better than the first two weeks.
I learned lots of new stuff, stuff that would greatly help me in my profession. I made friends with new people. But most important of all, I got some feedback on some of the things I do in life. It was kind of very scary, to be honest. But then I realized that the feedback will let me improve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Journal</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/08/08/bangalore-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/08/08/bangalore-journal/</guid>
      <description>This is my 13th day in Bangalore. And the first week of my training at ToughtWorks has gone by. I learned lots of stuff, talked to some great people and made friends with some of them. I still have not overcome the difficulties of adapting to life in the City. May be I will soon, or I never will.
I had planned to post everyday about my experiences in TWU. But I did not have much time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ajmal Qasab and his friends should hang their heads in shame</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/04/16/ajmal-qasab-and-his-friends-should-hang-their-heads-in-shame/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/04/16/ajmal-qasab-and-his-friends-should-hang-their-heads-in-shame/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I happened to watch the show &amp;lsquo;The Buck Stops Here&amp;rsquo; presented by Barkha Dutt on NDTV 24 X 7.
The trial of Ajmal Qasab, the lone terrorist captured during the Nov.27 attack on Mumbai and fellow defendants had begun in Mumbai and the court relieved Anjali Waghmare, the lawyer appointed by the court to defend Qasab, because of what it saw as a conflict of interest. Anjali Waghmare is the wife of a policeman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When I used to love Cricket</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/02/26/when-i-used-to-love-cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/02/26/when-i-used-to-love-cricket/</guid>
      <description>Taking a tour through the orkut albums of some of my friends from my school, I happened to see a photo of us in the playground, shot after a game of cricket. And there I was - thin, short and most surprisingly for me, with a cricket bat in my hand. True, I have seen the photo a number of times, I had even commented on it, but today, the bat in my hand reminding me solidly that I once used to play cricket and love it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Birthdays and Anniversaries</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/01/30/of-birthdays-and-anniversaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/01/30/of-birthdays-and-anniversaries/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we celebrated the birthday of one of my friends. There was not much of celebration per se, we just went to his place, talked a lot and had food from a restaurant. The restaurant bill was paid by the three guests, and not the host, but that is another story.
It had been a long since the four of us had come together, and so we talked about all stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tough Love</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/01/18/tough-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2009/01/18/tough-love/</guid>
      <description>I am about to finish my college within five months. As almost everyone at this juncture of life would have done, I am already beginning to look back at it. And nothing resurfaces from my memory like that of how it all began.
I still remember those days after I had finished school, when I had not decided what I wanted to do. Of course, I wanted to study, but higher education did not look a feasible prospect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Athletic Bilbao - Warriors in a world of Mercenaries</title>
      <link>https://sdqali.in/blog/2008/11/08/athletic-bilbao---warriors-in-a-world-of-mercenaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sdqali.in/blog/2008/11/08/athletic-bilbao---warriors-in-a-world-of-mercenaries/</guid>
      <description>Modern day football has become a professional game of the highest order, where money speaks loudest, player loyalty is as rare as silverware for ManCity, and big clubs poach youngsters from clubs with smaller financial muscle, with trick or crook.
Amidst all these there still stand a club, who recruit players from their locality, born to their tribe and is even ready to forsake their top-flight status, in order to stick to their principles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>