<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>geojson on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/categories/geojson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in geojson on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sadique.io/categories/geojson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Disputed territories and merging shapes and features</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2014/08/08/disputed-territories-and-merging-shapes-and-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2014/08/08/disputed-territories-and-merging-shapes-and-features/</guid>
      <description>Making a map that shows a disputed territory can be a tricky business. Nation states vigorously contest maps that appear to portray a boundary that challenges what a border looks like. From the Falkland Islands to Kuril Islands; from Western Sahara to Arunachal Pradesh, disputed territories result in omissions, additions and inaccuracies in maps.
I grew up looking at maps in books printed by the Oxford Press, that came with a disclaimer in blue rubber stamped across them that stated how the map was wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A list of GIS tools</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2014/08/03/a-list-of-gis-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2014/08/03/a-list-of-gis-tools/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with maps a lot these days and have ended up using various tools in the process. This blog post is a way to make a note of these tools for later use.
geojson.io Mapbox&amp;rsquo;s geojson.io is a simple tool for creating, editing and sharing maps. It lets you import map data in various formats and has an editor to modify maps.
GeoJSON-TopoJSON Jeff Paine&amp;lsquo;s GeoJSON-TopoJSON is a simple tool to convert between the more common GeoJSON format and the TopoJSON format used by libraries like D3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>