<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Malabar on {code that works}</title>
    <link>https://sadique.io/tags/malabar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Malabar on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2008-2025 Sadique Ali.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sadique.io/tags/malabar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The SNDP - NSS political experiment of 1980s</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2014/02/09/the-sndp-nss-political-experiment-of-1980s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2014/02/09/the-sndp-nss-political-experiment-of-1980s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, at the annual congregation of the Sree Narayana Dharma Paripalana (S.N.D.P.) Yogam, it&amp;rsquo;s leaders - Vellaapalli Nadesan and his son Thushaar announced that the Yogam is about to form their own political party that will unite Hindus of Kerala under one umbrella. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; S.N.D.P. and it&amp;rsquo;s leaders are no strangers to threatening to announce their intent to form a political party. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; They did the same in 2012, generating much talk in Kerala&amp;rsquo;s political landscape. The latest announcement is likely to suffer the same fate as these earlier announcements. To understand why the Yogam is highly unlikely to form a party of their own, one needs to look at the time when they indeed had their own political party - to the late 1970s; and the 1980 election to the Kerala legislature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fireworks in the paddy fields - memories of a summer</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/05/27/fireworks-in-the-paddy-fields-memories-of-a-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2013/05/27/fireworks-in-the-paddy-fields-memories-of-a-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like most people, I like certain songs for their ability to bring back memories of times, places and people from the past that you don&amp;rsquo;t everyday bring out from the cellars of time, wipe away the cobwebs and dust and gaze at. &lt;em&gt;Kannu Nattu Kaathirunnittum&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from the movie &lt;em&gt;Kathaavasheshan&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; evokes memories of childhood, the daily struggle to survive and the inability to resist the hegemony of those around you who call the shots. But, there are not many songs that does it for me quite like the Malayalam song &lt;em&gt;Alliyaambal Kadavil&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giving up the Samba for the Tiki-taka</title>
      <link>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/21/giving-up-the-samba-for-the-tiki-taka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sadique.io/blog/2012/08/21/giving-up-the-samba-for-the-tiki-taka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A shot flew over the bar. The goal keeper showed great urgency in&#xA;collecting the ball from behind the goal. Instead of kicking it forward, he pushed the ball&#xA;gently out to the centre back. As the opposition forward streamed&#xA;forward to close him down, the defender moved the ball swiftly and pushed it to&#xA;the right back who was level with the penalty box. Another push and the&#xA;central mid fielder was brought in to the play. A through ball to the&#xA;left found the player on the left wing and as the opposing&#xA;right back zoomed in to focus, he played it back to his left back. As&#xA;the left back controlled the ball, his&#xA;team repositioned themselves to start from scratch all over again. To build&#xA;from the back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have watched football in the recent past, you would recognise a&#xA;pattern here. You would see the unmistakable Barcelona blueprint. Except&#xA;that I am not describing Barcelona. Not even Spain. In fact when the&#xA;initial shot flew over the bar, there was no collective sigh of relief&#xA;from a crowd &lt;a href=&#34;%22http://mkbarcelona.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/200311-005.jpg%22&#34;&gt;packed till the heavens&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;there was no eager ball boy to throw the ball back at the keeper and&#xA;there was no one in the dug out shouting instructions at the&#xA;players. Hell, there was not even a dug out near the touch line. The&#xA;keeper ran to the construction site where the ball had found it&amp;rsquo;s way&#xA;through and ran back all the way to get the play restarted. As he was&#xA;still was running back, the left back of my opponents walked back to his&#xA;position, his face embellished with a smile bore out of his pride&#xA;of having bent his shot around the cashew tree inside the&#xA;ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
