<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on {code that works}</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/page/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=feed</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on {code that works}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/page/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=feed</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=feed</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a passionate software developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my career at ThoughtWorks, building integrations and plugins for Mingle - their project management / collaboration tool. I went on to work on Twist, where we pushed the boundaries of what a functional testing tool could do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I moved to San Francisco to help migrate Mingle from an on-premise model to a SaaS offering on Amazon AWS technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the next 3.5 years helping ThoughtWork&amp;rsquo;s partners and clients solve challenging technological problems - from Content Management Systems to E-commerce Microservices to in-store grocery picking solutions to Payment and Disbursement systems to Banking Portals, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2018 to 2021, I worked at Braintree in their Bank Payments team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently work as a Principal Engineer at Guaranteed Rate Companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find my blog posts useful, you should consider sending me a note to @sdqali / sadiqalikm AT gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/talks/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=feed</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/talks/?utm_source=site&amp;utm_medium=feed</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once in a while I garner enough courage, go stand in front of a crowd and talk about things that I like and/or have worked on. These are the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/categories/talk&#34;&gt;remnants&lt;/a&gt; of some of those incidents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
